<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lizziehop/reading-cookbooks/main/reading-cookbooks%20TEI/cookbook.odd.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>CHAPTER XLII. FRUIT SYRUPS, CORDIALS, ETC.</title>
                <title type="chapter" xml:lang="en"/>
                <sponsor>Center for Textual Studies and Digital Humanities, Loyola University Chicago</sponsor>
                <principal>
                    <persName>Elizabeth Hopwood</persName>
                </principal>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Transcription by</resp>
                    <persName>Eliora Horst</persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>First round encoding by</resp>
                    <persName>Anna Kroon</persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Second round encoding by</resp>
                    <persName>
                        <!-- insert name --></persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Proofreading by</resp>
                    <persName>
                        <!-- insert name --></persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Editorial research by</resp>
                    <persName>
                        <!-- insert name --></persName>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>

            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Reading Cookbooks Project</authority>
                <publisher><persName>Elizabeth Hopwood</persName> and The Center for Textual Studies and Digital Humanities</publisher>
                <availability>
                    <p>Reproduced by digitized version from Archive.org, contributed by <name>Cornell University Library</name>. There are no known
                        copyright restrictions in the United States on the use of the texts. More information on rights issues associated with public
                        domain texts can be found at https://www.library.cornell.edu/about/policies/public-domain</p>
                    <p>This text may be freely distributed for personal use, research, and teaching (including distribution to classes) as long as
                        this statement of availability is included in the text. It may be linked to freely in Internet editions of all kinds.</p>
                    <p>Scholars interested in changing or adding to these texts (for example, creating a new edition or adding additional markup) may
                        do so.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>

            <sourceDesc>

                <bibl>
                    <title>The Picayune's Creole Cook Book</title>
                    <publisher>New Orleans, La., The Picayune</publisher>
                    <date>1910</date>
                    <edition>4th</edition>
                    <sponsor>Cornell University Library</sponsor>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <p>This editions provides editorial notes</p>
            <editorialDecl>
                <p>Page breaks and column breaks have been preserved whenever possible. Abbreviations and spellings have been maintained. Line breaks
                    have not been encoded. All presentational elements such as alignments, all caps, bold, and italics will be encoded.</p>
                <normalization method="silent">
                    <p>Typos have been maintained</p>
                </normalization>
                <hyphenation eol="none">
                    <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of columns or lines have been reformed</p>
                </hyphenation>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <!-- Add date, initials, and what the change was -->
            <change when="2020-10-26" who="EAH">Created header and test template</change>
            <change when="2020-11-2" who="AMK">Added transcription to template and began encoding page 312</change>
            <change when="2020-11-6" who="AMK">Encoded element level tags</change>
            <change when="2020-11-9" who="AMK">Added attributes to elements</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="chapter">
                <pb n="312"/>
                <head rend="align(center) case(allcaps)">Chapter XLII.</head>
                <!-- start column one -->
                <head rend="align(center) case(allcaps) bold">Fruit Syrups, Cordials, Etc.</head>
                <head rend="align(center)">
                    <foreign xml:lang="fr">Des Sirops, des Liqueurs, Etc.</foreign>
                </head>
                <div type="prefatory">
                    <p>No book on <name>Creole</name> cookery would be complete without reference to those delightful fruit syrups which, under the
                        names of <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Sirops,"</foreign>
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Ratafias,"</foreign>
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Granits,"</foreign> etc., enter so largely into the home and social life of the <name>Creoles</name>.
                        Again, the ancient <name>Creole</name> housekeepers are famous for the delicious <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Cordials"</foreign>
                        or <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Liqueurs"</foreign> that they put up each year. Anisette as grateful to the palate as that
                        manufactured by the famous French distilleries is made at home by the <name>Creoles</name>, as also various kinds of domestic
                        wines, than which a better quality could not be purchased from professional manufacturers.</p>
                    <p>Before entering into a discussion of these <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Sirops"</foreign> and <foreign xml:lang="fr"
                            >"Liqueurs,"</foreign> the Picayune will refer to the ancient custom the <name>Creoles</name> have of serving sweetened
                        water after a hearty meal, and which, under the name of <hi rend="case(allcaps) bold"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Eau
                                Sucrée</foreign>,</hi> has been handed down from generation to generation as an integral part of the life of the
                            <name>Creole</name> household.</p>
                    <p>To one glass of fresh water allow one tablespoonful of sugar, or to a half glass allow a half tablespoonful stir till the sugar
                        is dissolved, and drink after a hearty meal. Every old <name>Creole</name> clings to his glass of <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Eau
                            Sucré."</foreign> He claims that this custom accounts for the singular freedom that the <name>Creoles</name>, as a rule,
                        enjoy from that distressing complaint, becoming so common in America — Dyspepsia. It is the rarest thing in the world to hear
                        a <name>Creole</name> complain of any <choice><sic>stomachic</sic><corr>stomach</corr></choice> trouble, notwithstanding heavy
                        dinners, numbers of courses, and richest viands and wines. The Eau Sucrée is passed around the table at the close of the meal,
                        and the children, as well as their elders, enjoy the drink. Again "Eau Sucré" is used by all <name>Creole</name> mothers as a
                        sedative for their little ones. Just before kissing her babes "Good-night," the <name>Creole</name> mother will give them a
                        small glass of <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Eau Sucrée."</foreign> It is claimed that it insures digestion and perfect sleep.</p>
                    <p><foreign xml:lang="fr">"Eau Sucré"</foreign> parties were famous in old New Orleans in those happy, innocent days when friend
                        met friend in social gatherings for the pleasure of social intercourse, and <!-- end column one --><!-- start column two -->
                        not for the sake of the grand spread of fancy viands and wines that have become such a source of terror in our day to the
                        housewife of limited means who wishes to entertain her friends. "With that beautiful old-time courtesy so peculiar to the
                            <name>Creoles</name>, the poor young woman who entertained was placed on an equal with her richer sister, for it became a
                        kind if unwritten law that beyond a glass of lemonade and cake, or a glass of <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Eau Sucrée,"</foreign>
                        nothing more was expected of the household. There was no tax. no drain; the faubourg laughed and sang and danced, night after
                        night, on Iced "Eau Sucrée," or Iced Lemonade, and Orgeats, and Ice Creams, with as much zest as when grand suppers were
                        spread and champagne flowed. There were no heartaches, no pangs, no sad thoughts, because Madame So-and-So, who lived in the
                        Rue Esplanade or Rue Rampart, had given a grander ball than her poorer sister, who lived in the Rue de Bons Enfants or the Rue
                        d'Amour. All this has passed away with the changing life of the old French quarter. But "Eau Sucrée" remains, and the Picayune
                        refers to it upon the merits claimed by the <name>Creoles</name>, that it promotes easy digestion and insures freedom from
                        insomnia. These claims are borne out by the longevity and good spirits for which the race is famous.</p>
                </div>

                <div type="orientationNote">
                    <head rend=" align(center) case(allcaps) bold">Syrups.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirops.</foreign></head> Under this heading are classed those delightful
                    beverages of fruits or nuts, served by the <name>Creole</name> housewives during the summer season. Of a hot, sultry day, if you
                    enter a well-regulated <name>Creole</name> household, the first thing Madame will do will be to regale you with a glass of
                    Lemonade, or "Iced Orgeat," or "Iced Pineapple," etc. The syrups are put up and bottled by Madame herself, and are always at hand.
                    Old "Tante Zizi," in bandana and tignon, knows the customs of the household well, and does not need to be told by Madame to
                    prepare a nice, cooling glass of <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Sirop"</foreign> for her guest. In a few moments you will see her enter
                    the parlor or sitting room with a dainty<pb n="313"/><!-- start column one -->silver salver, covered with a snowy napkin, and
                    bearing, according to the number of visitors, the glasses of iced <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Sirop."</foreign> Of an evening, as the
                    family sit out on the "Esplanade" or the gallery to enjoy the freshening breezes, she will come again unbidden to bring her
                    "people" the daily refreshing summer drink. It is all these pretty little customs and touches that make life in a
                        <name>Creole</name> household so pleasant and full of variety. </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">General Directions for Making Syrups.</head>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>The Plain Syrup, that is the basis of all fruit syrups, is simply sugar and water boiled together in the pro- portion of
                            two pounds of <ingredient>sugar</ingredient> to a pint and a half of <ingredient>water</ingredient>. Cook the sugar and
                            water till it forms the syrup called <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Le Petit Casse"</foreign> (see recipe under heading "Sugar as
                            Employed in Candy-Making"), or crack, that is, cook it till it instantly snaps asunder when placed between the fingers
                            after dipping them in cold water to enable one to test. Then add the Fruit Syrup, and mix thoroughly. Let it boil for
                            about five minutes; take off the fire and let it get almost cold, then bottle very tight. This is the invariable rule to
                            be followed in making syrups of fruits.</p>
                        <p>One quart of fruit when mashed and pressed will make a pint of Fruit Syrup, to be added to the Plain Syrup given above.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.2_apricot_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Apricot Syrup</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop d'Abricots.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>12 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Apricot Syrup</ingredient>. </item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Plain Syrup</ingredient>. </item>
                            <item>1 Ounce of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="extract">Essence of Apricots</ingredient>.</item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Pare and stone the apricots, then cut them into pieces, pound and mash well and set them aside for thirty-six hours in a
                            cool place. Then strain through a bag, pressing out all the juice. Cook the sugar and water till it forms the syrup called
                            "Le Petit Casse.' (See general directions for Making Syrups). Then add the apricot juice and mix thoroughly; let it boil
                            for five minutes, take off the fire, let it get almost cold, add the essence, and then bottle for use.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.3_banana_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Banana Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop de Bananes.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>2 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Banana Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Plain Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1/2 Ounce of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="extract"> Banana Essence.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>The <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Juice of a Lemon.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Peel the bananas, then cut into small pieces and pound and mash well and set aside in a cool place for thirty-six hours.
                            Then strain through a bag and proceed In ex<!-- end column one --><!-- start column two -->actly the same manner as for
                            Apricot Syrup (see recipe), and add the essence and lemon juice when about to bottle.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.4_blackberry_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Blackberry Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop de Mûres.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>1/2 Pint of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Blackberry Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Pick, stem and wash the blackberries, then pound and mash them well set aside in a cool place for thirty-six hours. Then
                            strain through a bag, pressing out all the juice, and proceed in exactly the same manner as for Apricot Syrup. (See
                            recipe.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.5_cherry_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Cherry Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop de Cerises.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>12 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Cherry Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Plain Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Seed the cherries, and stem, pound and mash them well, and let them stand for thirty-six hours in a cool place. Then strain
                            through a bag. Cook the sugar and water till it forms the syrup called "Le Petit Casse," or crack (see recipe under
                            chapter on <name>Creole</name> candies), that is, till it instantly snaps asunder when placed between the fingers, after
                            dipping them in cold water to enable you to test. Then add the fruit syrups and mix thoroughly. Let it boil for about five
                            minutes, take off the fire, let it get almost cold, and then put up in bottles.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.6_cranberry_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Cranberry Syrup. </head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop d'Airelles.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>2 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Cranberry Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Plain Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1/2 Ounce of Soluble <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="extract">Essence of
                                Lemon.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Proceed in exactly the same manner as for Currant Syrup (see recipe below), adding twice the quantity of sugar, and adding
                            the essence after the syrup has somewhat cooled and you are about to bottle it.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.7_currant_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Currant Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop de Groseilles.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>2 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Currant Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Plain Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Pick, seed, wash and dry the currants carefully. Then pound them well and set aside in a cool place for thirty-six hours.
                            Make a Plain Syrup (see recipe), and proceed as in the (general Directions for Making Fruit Syrups. (See directions.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.8_currant_syrup_with_raspberries">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Currant Syrup with Raspberries.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop de Groseilles Framboisée.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>1 Pint of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Currant Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>2 Pounds of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="sugar">Sugar.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>6 Pounds of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Currants.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Pound of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Sour Cherries.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Pound of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Raspberries.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 1/2 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Water.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>The cherries and raspberries are not necessary, but they give the sy<!-- end column two --><pb n="314"
                            /><!-- start column one -->rup a most delightful flavor and aroma. Pick, wash, seed and dry the currants carefully. Seed
                            the cherries, and stem them and the raspberries, pound and mash them well, and let them stand for thirty-six hours in a
                            cool place. Then strain through a bag. Cook the sugar and water till it forms the syrup called <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Le
                                Petit Cassé,"</foreign> or crack, that is, till it instantly when placed between the fingers, after dipping them in
                            cold water, to enable you to test. Then add the fruit syrups, and mix thoroughly. Let it boil for about five minutes, take
                            off the fire, let it get almost cold, and then put up in bottles.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.9_grape_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Grape Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop de Raisins.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>1 Gallon <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Plain Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>2 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Grape Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1/2 Pint of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="alcohol">Grape or Catawba
                                Wine.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Pick, wash, stem and seed the grapes; then pound and mash well, and set aside in a cool place for thirty-six hours. Then
                            strain through a bag, pressing out all the juice; make a Plain Syrup, and proceed in exactly the same manner as for
                            Currant Syrup, and add the wine when you are about to bottle.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.10_lemon_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Lemon Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop de Citron.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>8 Ounces of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Lemon Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>15 Ounces of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="sugar">Sugar.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1/2 Ounce of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="extract">Extract of Lemon.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Press the juice from the lemons and grate the zest of four into the syrup; set aside in a cool place for six or eight
                            hours. Then strain carefully through a bag. Make a Plain Syrup, using the proportions of fifteen ounces of sugar to a pint
                            and a half of water. Prepare a gallon of syrup, and then proceed as in the General Directions for Making Syrups (see
                            directions). Add the essence when about to bottle.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.11_lime_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Lime Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop de Limons.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>2 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Lime Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Plain Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1/2 Ounce of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="extract">Soluble Essence of
                                Limes.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Proceed in exactly the same manner as for Lemon Syrup, and add the essence when about to bottle.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.12_orange_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Orange Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop d'Orange.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>2 Quarts of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Orange Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Plain Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Ounce of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Lemon Juice.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Proceed in exactly the same manner as for Lemon Syrup, and bottle when almost cold. This is a standing <name>Creole</name>
                            Syrup.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <!-- end column one start column two -->
                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.13_orgeat_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Orgeat Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop d'Orgeat.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>1 Pound of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="nut">Sweet Almonds.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>4 Ounces of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="nut">Bitter Almonds.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>2 Pounds of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="sugar">Sugar.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Quart of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="water">Water.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>2 Ounces of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="???">Orange Flower
                                    Water.<!-- what is this? --></ingredient></item>
                            <item>The <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Zest of a Lemon.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Do not throw the almonds into hot water and' blanch them, as in other recipes for almonds, but throw them into cold water,
                            after shelling them, until the peeling or skin comes off easily. Then mash them and pound them in a mortar till they are
                            reduced to a fine powder, adding, from time to time, a little water and the well-grated zest of the lemon, When this paste
                            is perfectly made, moisten it with one-half of the water, and then squeeze it hard through a linen cloth, each end of
                            which is held by some one, when you will have drained thoroughly of all milk. Then return the paste to the mortar, throw
                            over the rest of the water, mix thoroughly, pounding well, and then squeeze again through the towel. Put the sugar into a
                            farina boiler, and let it boil to the degree of <foreign xml:lang="fr">"Le Petit Cassé,"</foreign> or crack,' that is,
                            till it forms a thick syrup that will not cling to the teeth in tasting, or instantly snaps asunder between the fingers
                            after testing in cold water. Then take the syrup off the fire and add the milk of almonds, stirring well. Return it to the
                            fire, and let it simmer gently till it begins to boil. Let it boil for several minutes. Then take it off the fire and let
                            it cool. When cold, add the orange flower water and mix well. Then drain all through a cloth or bag, and fill and seal the
                            bottles.</p>
                        <p>Orgeat, being made of the milk of almonds, easily decomposes or sours, because the oil of almonds, being lighter than the
                            other ingredients, rises to the top. For this reason, it is well to look at the bottles frequently, and shake them daily.
                            This will preserve the exact mingling of the mixture, and also preserve the Orgeat for use.</p>
                        <p>Orgeat is a great <name>Creole</name> syrup. It is not only a most delicate drink, but a healthy, popular and traditional
                            one. <!-- Interesting for contextual -->In old <name>Creole</name> households upon the birth of a babe, the friends who
                            call to congratulate the parents upon the new addition to the household are served with a glass of Orgeat, the mother
                            drinking with her friends in honor of the little angel just sent from heaven. This is an ancient <name>Creole</name>
                            custom, dating from earliest days in Louisiana.</p>
                        <p>Use only the finest white loaf sugar in making Orgeat Syrup.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <!-- end column two -->

                <!-- start column one -->
                <pb n="315"/>
                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.14_peach_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Peach Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop de Peches.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>2 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Peach Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Plain Syrup.</ingredient>
                            </item>
                            <item>1/2 Ounce of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="extract">Peach Essence.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Pare and stone the peaches, then pound and mash well and set aside in a cool place for thirty-six hours. Strain through a
                            bag, pressing out all the juice, then proceed in exactly the same manner as for Apricot Syrup, and add the essence as the
                            syrup cools and you are about to bottle it.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.15_pineapple_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Pineapple Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop d' Ananas.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>2 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Pineapple Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Plain Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Ounce of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Lemon Juice.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Pare the pineapples, cutting out the eyes and the core. Then cut into very fine pieces and mash and pound well, or grate
                            the pineapple, which is better. Set aside for thirty-six hours in a cool place. Then strain through a fine muslin bag,
                            pressing out all the juice. Then make a Plain Syrup and proceed as in the General Directions for Making Fruit Syrups. (See
                            directions.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.16_plum_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Plum Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop de Prunes.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>2 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Plum Juice.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Plain Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Stone the plums, pound and mash well and set aside in a cool place for thirty-six hours. Then proceed in exactly the same
                            manner as in the recipe for Apricot Syrup. (See recipe.)</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.17_strawberry_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Strawberry Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Syrop de Fraises.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>2 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Strawberry Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Plain Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Ounce of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="extract">Raspberry Essence.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Pick, stem and wash the strawberries, then pound and mash them well, and let them stand for thirty-six hours in a cool
                            place. Then strain through a bag. Cook the sugar and water till it forms the syrup called "Le Petit Cassé," or crack, that
                            is, till it instantly snaps asunder when placed between the fingers, after dipping them in cold water, to enable you to
                            test. Then add the fruit syrups, and mix thoroughly. Let it boil for about five minutes, take off the fire, let it get
                            almost cold, and then put up in bottles.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.17_strawberry_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Raspberry Syrup.</head>
                    <!-- missing french heading in text-->
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <!-- the recipe is an ingredient??? -->
                            <item>2 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Raspberry Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Gallon of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups">
                                    Plain Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Ounce of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="extract">Raspberry Esence.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Pick, stem and wash the berries and proceed in exactly the same manner as for Strawberry Syrup, adding the essence when
                            about to bottle.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <!-- end column one -->
                <!-- start column two -->
                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.19_vanilla_syrup">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Vanilla Syrup.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sirop de Vanille.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>1 Gallon of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic42.1_general_directions_for_making_syrups"
                                    >Plain Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>3 Ounces of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="extract">Extract of Vanilla.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1/4 ounce of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#"
                                    ><!-- need xml:id for caramel recipe -->Caramel.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Boil the syrup and add the Caramel. (See recipe.) Drain, and then add the essence of vanilla. Stir well and bottle.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.20_blackberry_vinegar">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Blackberry Vinegar.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Vinaigre de Mûres.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>2 Quarts of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Blackberries.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Quart of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Good French Vinegar.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Put one quart of blackberries into a jar or deep vessel, and pour over the vinegar. Let them stand for twenty-four hours
                            longer. Strain them again, and again add the fruit, repeating this operation and letting stand twenty-four hours three
                            times. Then strain through a muslin bag, and add one pound of white sugar to every pint of the liquor, and boil the whole
                            in a porcelain kettle for half an hour. When cold, bottle it and keep it in a cool place. Blackberry Vinegar made after
                            this manner will keep for years, improving with age.</p>
                        <p>Currant Vinegar and Cherry Vinegar are prepared in the same manner as above.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.21_orange_vinegar">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Orange Vinegar.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Vinaigre d'Oranges.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>36 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Oranges.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Quart of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Good French Cider.</ingredient></item>
                            <item><ingredient xxmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="sugar">Sugar</ingredient> in Proportion of Two-thirds of a
                                Pound to 1 Quart of <ingredient>Orange Syrup.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Peel the oranges. Slice them very thin and cover with pure cider vinegar, and let them stand for three of four days. Then
                            mash them through a cloth, straining as long as the juice runs clear. To every quart of juice allow one and two-thirds
                            pounds of fine white sugar. Then boil all together for about ten minutes, and skim very carefully, until no scum rises
                            upon the surface. Then take the mixture from the fire, and when it cools somewhat, bottle it. Put a tablespoonful of this
                            extract in a glass of cold ice water in warm weather, and you will have one of the most refreshing of the
                                <name>Creole</name> summer drinks.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.22_pineapple_vinegar">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Pineapple Vinegar.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Vinaigre d'Ananas.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>3 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Pineapples.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Quart of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Pure Cider Vinegar.</ingredient></item>
                            <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="sugar">Sugar</ingredient> In the Proportion of Two-thirds of
                                a Pound to One Quart of the Juice.</item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Cover the pineapples, which you will have nicely sliced, with pure cider vinegar, and let them stand for three or four
                            days. Then mash them through a cloth, straining as long as the juice runs clear. To every quart, of juice allow one and
                                <!-- end column two --><pb n="316"/><!-- start column one --> two-thirds pounds of fine white sugar. Then boil all
                            together for about ten minutes, and skim very carefully, until no scum rises upon the surface. Then take the mixture from
                            the fire, and when it cools somewhat bottle it. Put a tablespoonful of this extract in a glass of cold ice water in warm
                            weather, and serve as a summer drink.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.23_raspberry_vinegar">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Raspberry Vinegar.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Vinaigre de Framboises.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>2 Quarts of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Raspberries.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Quart of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Good French Vinegar.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Put one quart of raspberries into a jar or deep vessel, and pour over the vinegar. Let them stand for twenty-four hours,
                            and then strain through a jelly bag, and add the other quart of raspberries, and let them stand for twenty-four hours
                            longer. Strain them again, and again add the fruit, repeating this operation of straining and letting stand twenty-four
                            hours three times. Then strain through a muslin bag, and add one pound of white sugar to every pint of the liquor, and
                            boil the whole in a porcelain kettle for half an hour. When cold, bottle it and keep it in a cool place. Raspberry Vinegar
                            made ofter this man<!-- end column one --><!-- start column two -->ner will keep for years, improving with age. The
                                <name>Creoles</name> always keep it with Strawberry Vinegar or Blackberry Vinegar on hand, simply putting a
                            teaspoonful of it in a glass of sweetened ice water. It is a most refreshing summer beverage, and is especially grateful
                            to the sick and delicate.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic42.24_strawberry_vinegar">
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">Strawberry Vinegar.</head>
                    <head rend="align(center)">
                        <foreign xml:lang="fr">Vinaigre de Praises.</foreign>
                    </head>
                    <div type="ingredientList">
                        <list>
                            <item>2 Quarts of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Strawberries.</ingredient></item>
                            <item>1 Quart of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Good French Vinegar.</ingredient></item>
                        </list>
                    </div>
                    <div type="instructions">
                        <p>Put one quart of strawberries into a jar or deep vessel, and pour over the vinegar. Let them stand for twenty-four hours,
                            and then strain through a jelly bag, and add the other quart of strawberries, and let them stand for twenty-four hours
                            longer. Strain them again, and again add the fruit, repeating this operation of straining and letting stand twenty-four
                            hours three times. Then strain through a muslin bag and add one pound, of white sugar to every pint of the liquor, and
                            boil the whole in a porcelain kettle for half an hour. When cold, bottle it and keep it in a cool place.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
