<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lizziehop/reading-cookbooks/main/reading-cookbooks%20TEI/cookbook.odd.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>CHAPTER IV. FISH SOUPS.</title>
            <!-- Supply the title of chapter -->
            <title type="chapter" xml:lang="en"/>
            <sponsor>Center for Textual Studies and Digital Humanities, Loyola University Chicago</sponsor>
            <principal>Elizabeth Hopwood</principal>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Transcription by</resp>
               <persName>
                  Anna Kroon </persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>First round encoding by</resp>
               <persName>
                  Elizabeth Hopwood</persName> and <persName who="ppm">Prakruti Maniar</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Second round encoding by</resp>
               <persName>
                  Prakruti Maniar</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Proofreading by</resp>
               <persName>
                  <!-- insert name --></persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Editorial research by</resp>
               <persName>
                  <!-- insert name --></persName>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Reading Cookbooks Project</authority>
            <publisher><persName>Elizabeth Hopwood</persName> and The Center for Textual Studies and Digital Humanities</publisher>
            <availability>
               <p>Reproduced by digitized version from Archive.org, contributed by <name>Cornell University Library</name>. There are no known
                  copyright restrictions in the United States on the use of the texts. More information on rights issues associated with public
                  domain texts can be found at https://www.library.cornell.edu/about/policies/public-domain</p>
               <p>This text may be freely distributed for personal use, research, and teaching (including distribution to classes) as long as
                  this statement of availability is included in the text. It may be linked to freely in Internet editions of all kinds.</p>
               <p>Scholars interested in changing or adding to these texts (for example, creating a new edition or adding additional markup) may
                  do so.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc>
            
            <bibl>
               <title>The Picayune's Creole Cook Book</title>
               <publisher>New Orleans, La., The Picayune</publisher>
               <date>1910</date>
               <edition>4th</edition>
               <sponsor>Cornell University Library</sponsor>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <p>This editions provides editorial notes</p>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Page breaks and column breaks have been preserved whenever possible. Abbreviations and spellings have been maintained. Line breaks
               have not been encoded. All presentational elements such as alignments, all caps, bold, and italics will be encoded.</p>
            <normalization method="silent">
               <p>Typos have been maintained</p>
            </normalization>
            <hyphenation eol="none">
               <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of columns or lines have been reformed</p>
            </hyphenation>
         </editorialDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <!-- Add date, initials, and what the change was -->
         <change when="2020-10-26" who="EAH">Created header and test template</change>
         <change when="2020-11-05" who="PPM">Encoded the first four recipes</change>
         <change when="2020-11-14" who="PPM">Encoded the rest of the recipes, and changed ingredient 'type' to 'class'</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
     <body>
        <div type="chapter">
         <pb n="19"/> 
          <head rend="align(center) case(allcaps)">Chapter IV.</head>
          <head rend="align(center) case(allcaps) bold">Fish Soups.</head>
          <head rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Soupes de Poissons</foreign>.</head>
          <cb n="1" />
          <div type="prefatory">
               <p>Under this heading come some of the most delightful Creole soups, such as<name xml:id="pic4.2_green_turtle_soup"> Green Turtle
               Soup</name>, <name xml:id="pic4.7_oyster_soup">Oyster Soup</name>, <name xml:id="pic4.5_crawfish_bisque">Crawfish
                  Bisque</name>, etc. These not only serve as fast-day soups, but are considered elegant introductions to the most <foreign
                     xml:lang="fr">récherché</foreign> feast. </p>
            </div>
           <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic4.1_fish_soup">
               <head type="main" rend="align(center) bold">Fish Soup.</head>
               <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
               <foreign xml:lang="fr">Bouillon de Poisson.</foreign>
               </head>
            <div type="ingredientList">
               <list>
                  <item>6 Slices of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Fish</ingredient> of Almost Any Variety.</item>
                  <item> 4 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Onions</ingredient>, Chopped Fine.</item>
                  <item>6 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Tomatoes</ingredient>, Chopped Fine.</item>
                  <item>1 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Herb Bouquet</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>Sprig of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Parsley</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1 Glass of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="alcohol">White Wine</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item> 4 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">Salad Oil</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>4 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="grain">Flour</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>3 Pints of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Water</ingredient>.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div type="instructions">
               <p>Chop the onions and fry them in the salad oil. Cut the tomatoes fine and add onions, and put in all the other ingredients,
                  except the fish, adding the flour to make a good roux. When brown add the water, and, after it has boiled about a half hour,
                  add the slices of fish. When they are firm remove the herb bouquet, add <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0"    class="spice">Cayenne pepper</ingredient>, and <ingredient key="seasoning">salt</ingredient> and <ingredient key="seasoning">pepper</ingredient> 
                  to taste, and serve the fish soup in a tureen, pouring it over crusts of dried toast. </p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <cb n="2"/> 
           <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic4.2_green_turtle_soup">
            <head type="main" rend="align(center) bold">Green Turtle Soup.</head>
            <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
               <foreign xml:lang="fr">Soupe à la Tortue.</foreign>
            </head>
            <div type="ingredientList">
               <list>
                  <item>2 Pounds of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Turtle Meat</ingredient>, or a 2-Pound
                     Turtle.</item>
                  <item>2 Fine Large <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Onions</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>6 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Cloves</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1 Square inch of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="meat">Ham</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>6 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Allspice</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>2 Cloves of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="aromatic">Garlic</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>2 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="grain">Flour</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1/4 of a Small <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Lemon</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>2 Hard-Boiled <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">Eggs</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1 Glass of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="alcohol">Sherry Wine</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Parsley</ingredient>, <ingredient
                     xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Thyme</ingredient>, <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0"
                        type="herb">Bay Leaf</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="salt">Salt</ingredient>, <ingredient
                     xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Pepper</ingredient>, and <ingredient
                        xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Cayenne</ingredient> to Taste.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div type="orientationNote">
               <p>The <name>Creoles</name> pride themselves upon their famous "<foreign xml:lang="fr">Soupe à la Tortue</foreign>," and justly;
                  the old saying that only a good Creole cook knows how to make a good Turtle Soup being testified to by epicurean visitors from
                  every country.</p>
               <p>The following is one of the simplest and best ways of making Turtle Soup—a recipe that may always be relied upon and one that
                  has been used from generation to generation in the most aristocratic Creole homes:</p>
            </div>
            <div type="instructions">
               <p>In making Turtle Soup, remember that Green Turtle is always the best for this purpose. Select two pounds of fine Green Turtle
                  meat, if the turtle is not bought whole. This amount will make soup for six persons. Increase proportionately. If <pb n="20"
                  />the turtle is bought whole, first cut off the head. To do this properly, the turtle should be hung with the head downwards,
                  and a very sharp knife should be used to cut off the head as close as possible. Often for hours after this operation is
                  performed, the turtle will exhibit extraordinary signs of life, the flesh quivering constantly. The old <name>Creole
                     </name>cooks say that a turtle never dies, but this is a darky tradition. To remove the shells, first separate the upper
                  from the lower shell, always being exceedingly careful to avoid touching the gall bladder, which is very large. If this
                  bladder is penetrated, the contents running over the turtle meat would render it utterly unfit for use.</p>
               <p>Clean the turtle and the entrails by cutting open and washing thoroughly in cold water. Then put the meat and entrails into a
                  saucepan and parboil about ten minutes. Be careful to save this stock of water. Chop an onion very fine, and the ham into very
                  fine pieces. Cut the turtle meat into one-inch pieces, mash the cloves and the allspice very fine and chop the thyme and bay
                  leaf. Brown the onions in a tablespoonful of butter or lard, and add immediately the turtle meat. Brown together slightly and
                  after minutes add the chopped ham. Let this continue browning and then add two cloves of garlic, chopped fine, and the thyme,
                  bay leaf (minced fine), cloves and allspice (ground), all mixed together, and lay on the turtle. Stir this almost constantly
                  to prevent curing, and add two tablespoonfuls of flour that has been well rubbed, stirring constantly all the time. Then
                  dissolve the meat with the water in which the turtle was parboiled, adding gradually until a certain consistency is reached.
                  About three quarts of water will be the required amount. Season this with salt, black pepper and Cayenne to taste, and boil
                  slowly for fully an hour, stirring almost constantly. After cooking on hour taste, and if not seasoned sufficiently, season
                  again and taste. Then chop one-quarter of a small lemon and put it in the soup. Let it continue to cook, and when well
                  done—that is, when no blood exudes from the turtle after sticking it with a fork—pour into the tureen. Add the whites and
                  yolks of two hard-boiled eggs, chopped fine, and one good glass of Sherry wine. This is a dish fit for a king and is most
                  highly recommended as a genuine Creole Turtle Soup.</p>
               <p>If Quenelles or Forcemeat Balls are desired, they may be prepared according to the recipe given under <cb n="1"/>the heading
                  <name><!-- xml:id for quenelles, needs to be made -->"Quenelles."</name> (See recipe, under chapter "Stuffings and
                  Dressings," etc.)</p>
            </div>
          </div>
           <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic4.3_turtle_soup_no._2">
            <head type="main" rend="align(center) bold">Turtle Soup No. 2</head>
            <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
               <foreign xml:lang="fr">Soupe à la Tortue.</foreign>
            </head>
            <div type="ingredientList">
               <list>
                  <item>2 Pounds of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Turtle Meat</ingredient>, or a 2-Pound
                     Turtle.</item>
                  <item>1/2 Tablespoonful of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">Lard</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1/2 Tablespoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat"> Butter</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>2 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="grain">Flour</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>2 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Tomatoes</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1 Large <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Onion</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1 Sprig of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Thyme</ingredient>.     2 Sprigs of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" type="herb">Parsley.</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1 Square Inch of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="meat">Ham</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1 Dozen <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Cloves</ingredient> Tied in Muslin.</item>
                  <item>6 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Allspice </ingredient> Mashed Fine. </item>
                  <item>3 Quarts of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Water.</ingredient></item> 
                  <item>2 Hard-boiled<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">Eggs. </ingredient></item>
                  <item>1 Glass of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="alcohol">Sherry or White Wine</ingredient></item>
                  <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="salt">Salt</ingredient> and <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" type="spice">Cayenne</ingredient> to Taste.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div type="instructions">
               <p>Clean the turtle and entrails by cutting open the latter and washing thoroughly in cold water. Then put the meat and entrails into a saucepan 
                  and parboil them for ten minutes. Carefully save this stock of water. Chop the onion very fine, and cut the ham into very fine pieces. 
                  Cut the turtle meat into one-inch pieces; mash the allspice very fine, and mince the parsley, thyme and bay leaf. 
                  Then brown the onions in the lard and butter mixed, and almost immediately add the turtle meat. Brown together for ten 
                  minutes and add the finely chopped ham. As this continues to brown, add the cloves of garlic (minced fine), the thyme and bay 
                  leaf and the ground allspice. Mix all together, stirring almost constantly to prevent burning. Then add the well-rubbed 
                  tablespoonfuls of flour, stirring constantly. Scald and skin the tomatoes and chop them fine, and add to the turtle meat. 
                  When well-browned, pour over three quarts of the water in which the turtle was parboiled, season with salt and pepper and Cayenne to taste, 
                  and let it boil slowly for fully an hour, stirring frequently. After one hour, taste the soup, and, if not sufficiently seasoned, 
                  add seasoning of salt, pepper and Cayenne again, according to taste. Let it cook for an hour longer and then take off 
                  the stove if the turtle is thoroughly done. This may be ascertained by sticking it with a fork. 
                  If no blood exudes, the soup is ready to serve. Take off the stove and strain through a colander into the tureen. 
                  Add the whites and yolks of two hard-boiled eggs, chopped fine, and one good glass of Sherry or White Wine. 
                  Slice a lemon fine and add to the soup and serve hot.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="orientationNote">
               <head type="main" rend="align (center) bold">How to Serve Turtle Soup.</head>
               <p>
                  Great care should be taken in serving the soup. It should be borne in mind that boiling 
                  the soup a second time, or warming it over, deprives it of much of its delicious flavor. 
                  To avoid this, fill two tureens with boil-
                  <pb n="21"/>
                  ing water; let them stand a few minutes, then dry the inside thoroughly and place the tureens in a "bain-marie," of a hot-water bath. 
                  Fill the tureens with the soup and cover tightly. Bring them to the table as needed, throwing in just before serving, some dainty
                  slices of lemon. If the meat is served, use only the most delicate portions. 
               </p>
            </div> 
            <div type= “recipeAddition” corresp= “#pic4.1_fish_soup”>
                  <head type="main" rend="align (center) bold">Mock Eggs for Turtle Soup...</head>
                  <div type="instructions">
                     <p>Should the turtle possess no eggs, the following method of making mock eggs is often used. 
                        Break and beat thoroughly one fresh <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">egg</ingredient>; then take the 
                        yolks of three hard-boiled eggs, and rub them into a fine paste with about a teaspoonful of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">butter</ingredient>. Mix this with the raw egg and 
                        roll into pellets of the identical size and shape of the turtle eggs, let them lie in boiling <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">water</ingredient> about 
                        two minutes, and then drop into the soup.
                     </p>
                  </div>   
            </div>
          </div> 
           <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic4.5_terrapain_soup">
            <head type="main" rend="align(center) bold">Terrapin Soup</head>
            <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
               <foreign xml:lang="fr">Soupe à la Tortue.</foreign>
            </head>
           <div type="ingredientList">
             <list>
                <item>1 Two-Pound Diamond-Back <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Terrapin. </ingredient></item>
                <item>2 Fine Large <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Onion</ingredient>.</item>
                <item>6 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Cloves</ingredient>.</item>
                <item>1 Square Inch of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="meat">Ham</ingredient>.</item>
                <item>6 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Allspice</ingredient>.</item>
                <item>1/4 of a Small <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Lemon</ingredient>.</item>
                <item>2 Hard-Boiled <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">Eggs</ingredient>.</item>
                <item>1 Glass of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="alcohol">Sherry Wine</ingredient>.</item>
                <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Parsley, Thyme, and Bay Leaf</ingredient>.</item>
                <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="salt">Salt</ingredient>, 
                   <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Pepper</ingredient> and 
                   <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Cayenne</ingredient> . to Taste. </item>
              </list>
            </div>
            <div type ="orientationNote">
               <p>
                  Remember always that the land terrapin is unfit to eat. The fresh-water terrapin can be made into a most 
                  relishable article of food if cooked according to <name>Creole</name> methods. The diamond-back terrapin is the 
                  best and the females make the finest and daintiest food, the males being not only of inferior size, 
                  but of far less delicate flavor. Terrapins must always be bought alive. They are in season November till 
                  March, and, like all other fish, should not be eaten out of season. The red leg or fresh-water terrapin, 
                  or the terrapin of common variety, called "<name>Gopher</name>," are eschewed by the <name>Creoles</name>, but are good to eat. 
                  To have a good terrapin soup the diamond back must be used.
               </p>
               <div type="instructions">
                  <p>
                     To make the soup, clean the terrapin as you would a turtle. Then place in a kettle and boil till tender. 
                     Take out and cut into small pieces, saving the water. Proceed as for Turtle Soup. When it boils up take from the 
                     fire, add a grated nutmeg, a glass of Sherry or <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="alcohol">Madeira wine </ingredient>and serve.
                     The farci or forcemeat balls is made in exactly the same manner as for Turtle soup. Serve with green pickle and delicate slices of fried toast. 
                  </p>
                  <cb/>  
               </div>
            </div>   
         </div> 
           <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic4.6_crawfish_bisque">
            <head type="main" rend="align(center) bold">Crawfish Bisque.</head>
            <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
               <foreign xml:lang="fr">Potage à la Bisque d'Ecrevisse.
               </foreign>
            </head>
            <div type="ingredientList">
               <list>
                  <item>8 Dozen Fine Large <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Crawfish</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>3 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Onions</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Carrot</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1 Bunch of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Celery</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>2 Sprigs of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Thyme</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>2 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Bay Leaves</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>4 Sprigs of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Parsley</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>6 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Cloves</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>2 Blades of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="aromatic">Mace</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1 Clove of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="aromatic">Garlic</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>2 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="dairy">Butter</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>2 Quarts of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="alcohol">Oyster Liquor</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>A Dash of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Cayenne</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item>1 Seedless <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Cayenne Pod</ingredient>.</item>
                  <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="salt">Salt</ingredient> and <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">
                     Pepper</ingredient>to Taste.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <cb n="2"/>
            <div type="instructions">
               <p>Crawfish Bisque is a distinctive <name>Creole </name>luxury. It is prepared as follows:
               </p>
               <p>
                  Take about eight dozen fine, large crawfish and wash thoroughly being 
                  careful to cleanse of every particle of dust and sand. Set to boil in about 
                  a gallon of water. When boiled, take the fish out of the water; save the water. 
                  Pick out two dozen of the largest crawfish; pick out the inside of the tails 
                  and save the heads, cleansing them of every particle of meat. Set this meat to one 
                  side with the shells of the head. Pick the meat from the rest of the crawfish, saving 
                  all the shells. Take one large onion, a carrot, a bunch of celery, a sprig of thyme, 
                  one bay leaf, three sprigs of parsley, six cloves and two blades of mace, come clove of garlic; 
                  chop all very fine and put into the pot of water in which the crawfish were boiled. 
                  Add all the picked meat, except the reserved tails, and all the shells of the bodies 
                  and heads, except the reserved heads. Add one cup of rice and let it all boil till the mixture 
                  becomes thick and mushy. When it is well cooked, take it off the fire and mash the shells 
                  thoroughly, and the meat also, and strain all through a sieve. Take about a 
                  tablespoonful of butter and two quarts of oyster liquor and add this to the soup, 
                  seasoning to taste with Cayenne, salt and black pepper. Set to boil slowly. 
                  In the meantime, take the reserved crawfish meat and make a stuffing as follows 
                  for the reserve heads; chop an onion very fine and let brown in a 
                  tablespoonful of butter. Squeeze thoroughly a cup of bread wet with <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">water</ingredient>. 
                  When well squeezed, mix with a little <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="dairy">milk</ingredient>, sufficient to make a paste, 
                  season to taste and mix with the well-seasoned crawfish meat. 
                  Chop another onion and put in melted butter, and add the crawfish 
                  stuffing, letting all fry about ten minutes, ading, in the meantime, 
                  a finely-chopped sprig each of thyme and parsley and a bay leaf, 
                  and mixing thoroughly. Take off the fire and stuff the reserved head of 
                  crawfish. Put on every stuffed head a dot of butter, and set in the oven 
                  and bake ten minutes. Place the stuffed heads in the tureen and pour the soup over. 
                  Serve with hot <ingredient>Croutons</ingredient>
                  <pb n="22"/>
                  <cb n="1" />
                  of buttered toast passing the latter in a separate dish. 
               </p>
            </div>   
          </div>
           <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic4.7_crawfish_soup">
               <head type="main" rend="align(center) bold">Crawfish Soup.</head>
               <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
                  <foreign xml:lang="fr">Potage d'Écrevisses. 
                  </foreign>
               </head>
               <div type="ingredientList">
                  <list>
                     <item>50 Fine Large <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Crawfish</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>1 1/2 finds of a Fillet of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="meat">Veal</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>1 Slice of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="meat">Ham</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>1 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Herb Bouquet</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>1 Half Can of of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="">Mushrooms</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>2 Tablespoonfuls of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="grain">Flour</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>2 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Carrots</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>1 Tablespoonful of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="dairy">Butter</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>1 Clove of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="aromtiac">Garlic</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>1 Large <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Onion</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>1 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Parsnip</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>1 Dozen <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="nut">Almonds</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>1 Dozen <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Allspice</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>4 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Shallots</ingredient>.</item>
                     <item>6 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Tomatoes</ingredient> or a Half Can.</item>
                     <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="">Croutons</ingredient>.</item>
                  </list>
               </div>
                  <div type="instructions">
                     <p>Wash the crawfish thoroughly over and over again to take away every 
                        particle of dust. Then boil them in plain <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">water</ingredient>. Save the water. Take out the 
                        crawfish and take off all the shells, putting the meat aside. Pound the 
                        shells fine; pound one dozen almonds fine and mix thoroughly with the 
                        meat of the crawfish and pound this in a mortar. In the meanwhile, 
                        take one pound and a half of a filet of veal and a slice of ham and 
                        cut in small pieces. Cut up the onion, carrots and parsnips. Put one 
                        tablespoonful of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">lard</ingredient> in a kettle, and when it begins to heat, add the 
                        herb bouquet (sweet basil, parsley, bay leaf), the onions, parsnips, 
                        shallots, clove of garlic, chopped fine; as these brown, add the veal and ham. 
                        Add two tablespoonfuls of flour and butter rubbed, and the mushrooms, chopped finely. 
                        Let these simmer for about five minutes and then add the tomatoes, allspice and cloves. 
                        After ten minutes, when the mixture is well browned, add the pounded 
                        crawfish shells and the pounded meat and almonds. Pour over all the water 
                        from the boiled crawfish and set it back on the stove and let it simmer for about 
                        two hours. Skim off all grease when near time for serving. Then strain through a 
                        sieve and serve with <ingredient>Croutons</ingredient> of toast, cut in slices, placed in the bottom of the tureen. </p>
                        <p>On fast days, instead of the veal and ham, substitute butter and 
                           lard making a <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="">Roux (see recipe)</ingredient>, and moistening a little with the 
                           stock of the crawfish. Then proceed as above.</p>
                     <p><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="grain">Rice</ingredient> or <ingredient>Crouton Soup</ingredient> is rendered delicious by introducing a small quantity 
                           of the broth of the crawfish. The broth is also used extensively 
                           by the <name>Creoles</name> in seasoning ragouts on fast days, and hot pies such 
                        as pâtés de flies gras; also such entrémets as <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">cauliflower</ingredient>,
                        <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">artichokes</ingredient>, etc. The chief essential in making the <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">broth</ingredient> is to have 
                        it of the right consistency, and to skim carefully of all the grease before straining. Good judgement must be the guide of the cook in seeking the proper consistency.</p>
                  </div>
            </div>
          <cb n="2"/> 
           <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic4.8_oyster_soup">
             <head type="main" rend="align(center) bold">Oyster Soup.</head>
             <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
                <foreign xml:lang="fr">Soupe aux Huîtres.
                </foreign>
             </head>
             <div type="ingredientList">
                <list>
                   <item>4 Dozen Large, Fresh <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Oysters</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>1 Quart of Rich <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="dairy">Milk</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>The <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Oyster Liqor</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>1 Tablespoonful of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="dairy">Butter</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>3 Sprigs of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Parsley</ingredient>, Chopped Fine.</item>
                   <item>1 Dozen <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Peppercorns</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="salt">Salt</ingredient>and 
                      <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Pepper</ingredient>to Taste.</item>
                </list>
             </div>
             <div type="instructions">
                <p>
                   In purchasing the oysters always be careful to make the vendor 
                   add the <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">oyster juice</ingredient> when intended for soup. In making good oyster soup the 
                   <name>Creoles</name> never use any water, but the liquor from the oysters. Drain the oysters 
                   through a colander and set them over the ice box to keep fresh and cold. 
                   Strain the liquor, and put it into a soup kettle, adding the chopper parsley and the 
                   pepper corns. Let it come to a boil. In the meantime, boil the milk 
                   separately in a saucepan, as boiling the milk and oyster joule together is likely 
                   to curdle the milk. When the milk comes to a boil, add to the oyster juice and put 
                   in the tablespoonful of butter. Some thicken the soup by adding a tablespoonful of 
                   <ingredient>corn starch</ingredient>, rubbing it into the four before putting it in the soup. But this is 
                   a matter of taste. If the milk is rich and good, the soup will require no 
                   thickening, and is far daintier without it. Stir the soup constantly at this 
                   point, throwing in the oysters and continuing to stir until it comes to a boil again. 
                   Under no circumstances allow the oysters to boil, as that destroys their flavor 
                   and makes them tough and indigestible. But one must also be careful to see that 
                   they are steamed through and through, and then they are delightful and palatable. 
                   The crowning triumph in making oyster soup is to have the oysters cook just enough. 
                   The ruffling of the edges indicates the right conditions at this point the soup 
                   must be served immediately. Serve with sliced <ingredient  xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">lemon</ingredient> and oyster or <ingredient>water crackers</ingredient>. 
                   Some added a little <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">nutmeg</ingredient> and <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">mace</ingredient>, and, still again, some <name>Creoles</name> place chopped 
                   <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">celery</ingredient> in exceedingly small quantities, and a herb bouquet into the oyster juice, 
                   being careful to allow it to give just the desired flavor, and taking it out before 
                   adding the milk. But this, too, is a matter of taste. Made according to the above 
                   formula, oyster soup is a most delightful dish and can be eaten and relished by the 
                   most delicate stomachs.
                </p>
             </div>
          </div>
           <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic4.9_oyster_soup_without_milk">
             <head type="main" rend="align(center) bold">COyster Soup Without Milk</head>
             <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
                <foreign xml:lang="fr">Soup aux Huîtres à la Creole. 
                </foreign>
             </head>
             <div type="orientationNote">
                <p>The Creoles have another delightful method of preparing oyster soup, 
                   a method evolved by the old negro cooks of ante-bellum days, and 
                   still in vogue in the ancient families.</p>
             </div>
             <pb n="23"/>
             <cb n="1"/>
             <div type="ingredientList">
                <p>It is a soup made without milk and is prepared as follows: Take
                </p>
                <list>
                   <item>4 Dozen Bayou Cook <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Oysters</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>The <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Oyster Liquor</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>1 Large <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Onion</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>1 Tablespoonful of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">Lard</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>2 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="grain">Sifted Flour</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>4 Sprigs of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Parsley</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>1 Tablespoonful of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="dairy">Butter</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>1 Quart of Boiling <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Water</ingredient>.</item>
                </list>
             </div>
             <div type="instructions">
                <p>
                   Put the table spoonful of lard into the soup kettle. Have ready onion, some 
                   parsley, chipped very fine. When the lard is hot, stir in two tablespoonfuls of sifted flour, 
                   and make a <ingredient>Brown Roux (see recipe)</ingredient>, stirring constantly to prevent burning. When 
                   the Roux is of a light brown color, add the chopped onions and parsley, continuing to stir, 
                   being exceedingly careful to avoid the semblance of burning. Strain the oyster 
                   juice of about four dozen oysters into the Roux, mixing thoroughly. to avoid bits 
                   of shell; mix with about a quart of boiling water and pour When it shouts signs 
                   of coming to a boil, off the oysters and a teaspoonful of butter. At the boiling 
                   point reprove from the stove and serve with oyster soda crackers or dry toast, 
                   the oyster crackers being always preferable.
                <p>
                </p>
                   This form of soup may be improved by using the <ingredient>milk</ingredient> instead of the hot water, 
                   but either way is very pal<cb n="2"/>atable 
                   and a great favorite as a fast-day soup.</p>
             </div>   
                
          </div>  
           <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic4.10_crab_soup">
             <head type="main" rend="align(center) bold">Crab Soup.
             </head>
             <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
                <foreign xml:lang="fr">Potage de Crabes.
                </foreign>
             </head>
             <div type="ingredientList">
                <list>
                   <item>1 Dozen Fine <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Crabs</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>6 Ripe <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Tomatoes</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>1 Sprig of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Thyme</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>3 Sprigs of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Parsley</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>1 of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Sweet Marjoram</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>1 Large <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Onion</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>1 Clove of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="aromatic">Garlic</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>1 Teaspoonful of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="dairy">Butter</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>2 Tablespoonfuls of (level) <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">Lard</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item>1 <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Lemon</ingredient>.</item>
                   <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="salt">Salt</ingredient>,
                      <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Pepper</ingredient> and
                      <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Cayenne</ingredient>.</item>
                </list>
             </div> 
             <div type="instructions">
                <p>
                   Cleanse the crabs thoroughly and extract all the meat from 
                   the body and claws; scald and skin tomatoes, and squeeze the 
                   pulp from the seeds and juice; chop very fine. Pour boiling water 
                   over the seed and juice and strain. Chop the onion and garlic and 
                   stew with the tablespoonful of butter and lard. As they begin to brown, 
                   add the tomatoes, cover, and, after simmering a few minutes, add 
                   the well-seasoned meat of the crab. Sift over this some grated bread 
                   or crackers and season with Cayenne, sweet marjoram and thyme. Pour 
                   in tomato water and add about a quart or more of water, and let it boil 
                   moderately for about an hour. Add the juice of two lemons and serve.  
                </p>
             </div>   
          </div>      
        </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
© 2020 GitHub, Inc.
Terms
Privacy
Security
Status
Help
Contact GitHub
Pricing
API
Training
Blog
About
