<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lizziehop/reading-cookbooks/main/reading-cookbooks%20TEI/cookbook.odd.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>CHAPTER XLVII</title>
                <!-- Supply the title of chapter -->
                <title type="chapter" xml:lang="en"/>
                <sponsor>Center for Textual Studies and Digital Humanities, Loyola University
                    Chicago</sponsor>
                <principal>
                    <persName>Elizabeth Hopwood</persName>
                </principal>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Transcription by</resp>
                    <persName>Ve'Amber Miller</persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>First round encoding by</resp>
                    <persName>Regina Hong</persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Second round encoding by</resp>
                    <persName>
                        <!-- insert name --></persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Proofreading by</resp>
                    <persName>
                        <!-- insert name --></persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Editorial research by</resp>
                    <persName>
                        <!-- insert name --></persName>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>

            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Reading Cookbooks Project</authority>
                <publisher><persName>Elizabeth Hopwood</persName> and The Center for Textual Studies
                    and Digital Humanities</publisher>
                <availability>
                    <p>Reproduced by digitized version from Archive.org, contributed by
                            <name>Cornell University Library</name>. There are no known copyright
                        restrictions in the United States on the use of the texts. More information
                        on rights issues associated with public domain texts can be found at
                        https://www.library.cornell.edu/about/policies/public-domain</p>
                    <p>This text may be freely distributed for personal use, research, and teaching
                        (including distribution to classes) as long as this statement of
                        availability is included in the text. It may be linked to freely in Internet
                        editions of all kinds.</p>
                    <p>Scholars interested in changing or adding to these texts (for example,
                        creating a new edition or adding additional markup) may do so.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>

            <sourceDesc>

                <bibl>
                    <title>The Picayune's Creole Cook Book</title>
                    <publisher>New Orleans, La., The Picayune</publisher>
                    <date>1910</date>
                    <edition>4th</edition>
                    <sponsor>Cornell University Library</sponsor>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <p>This editions provides editorial notes</p>
            <editorialDecl>
                <p>Page breaks and column breaks have been preserved whenever possible.
                    Abbreviations and spellings have been maintained. Line breaks have not been
                    encoded. All presentational elements such as alignments, all caps, bold, and
                    italics will be encoded.</p>
                <normalization method="silent">
                    <p>Typos have been maintained</p>
                </normalization>
                <hyphenation eol="none">
                    <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of columns or lines have been
                        reformed</p>
                </hyphenation>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <!-- Add date, initials, and what the change was -->
            <change when="2020-10-26" who="EAH">Created header and test template</change>
            <change when="2020-11-23" who="RH">Added transcription to template and began
                encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="chapter">
                <pb n="356"/>
                <head rend="align(center) case(allcaps)"> Chapter XLVII.</head>
                <head type="main" rend="bold">Creole Breads.</head>
                <head type="sub">
                    <foreign xml:lang="fr">Des Pains à la Créole.</foreign>
                </head>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="prefatory">
                    <p> Perhaps no branch of <name>Creole</name> cookery so interests visitors to
                        New Orleans as our <name>Creole</name> Breads. While in breakfast relishes,
                        such as batter cakes, flannel cakes, waffles, buckwheat cakes, biscuit, etc.
                        we have much in common with out sections, there is a distinctiveness about
                        our “Brioches,” “Babas,” “Calas,” “Sacamités,” “Sweet Potato Bread,” French
                        Loaves, French Rolls, etc., which are peculiar to ourselves alone. Our
                        “Baker’s Bred,” or “Pain de Boulanger,” of itself stands unique among the
                        breads of the United States, and has been the subject of more than one
                        interesting newspaper and magazine article. It has this peculiarity, that
                        one never tries if it, as they do of other breads, and the reason for this
                        is that it is of exquisite lightness, white and tender , of an even porous
                        character, with a thin, crisp crust, and, best of all, is just such a bread
                        as is required in our climate. Made into toasts, it is the most delightful
                        of all breads, no home-made light bread or bakers’ bread in any other part
                        of the United States standing comparison with it. Bakers’ Bread is the daily
                        offering, morning,
                   <cb n="2"/> 
                        noon and night, on every New Orleans table. 
                    </p>
                    <p> 
                        Out “Calas” are famous, and have been treated on under the chapter on
                        Louisiana Rice, while our “Brioches” are not only the joy of the natives,
                        but the delight of visitors from all parts of the country. A cup of Cafè
                        Noir in the French Market and a Brioche is one of the standing treats to
                        which every visitor to New Orleans is invited. 
                    </p>
                    <head rend="align(center) bold">How to Make and Bake Bread.</head>
                    <p>
                        Bread, to be perfect, should be light and sweet, with a rich nutty flavor of the wheat. 
                        To obtain this result, only the best flour and the best dough must be used. 
                        While the bread is rising the temperature of the oven should be at the 75 degrees Fahrenheit, 
                        and the heat of the oven in baking should be about 360 degrees, or hot enough to raise the inside 
                        of the bread to about 220 degrees. This is necessary to cook the starch, expand the carbonic gas, 
                        steam and air, and also to drive off the alcohol which is used in the yeast. 
                        The bakers in New Orleans have a way of testing the temperature of the oven by putting a piece of white paper in it. If 
                    </p>                   
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
