<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lizziehop/reading-cookbooks/main/reading-cookbooks%20TEI/cookbook.odd.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>CHAPTER XXII. SALADS. </title>
        <!-- Supply the title of chapter -->
        <title type="chapter" xml:lang="en"/>
        <sponsor>Center for Textual Studies and Digital Humanities, Loyola University Chicago</sponsor>
        <principal><persName>Elizabeth Hopwood</persName></principal>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Transcription by</resp>
          <persName>Elizabeth Hopwood</persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>First round encoding by</resp>
          <persName>Regina Hong</persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Second round encoding by</resp>
          <persName>
            <!-- insert name --></persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Proofreading by</resp>
          <persName>
            <!-- insert name --></persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Editorial research by</resp>
          <persName>
            <!-- insert name --></persName>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      
      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>Reading Cookbooks Project</authority>
        <publisher><persName>Elizabeth Hopwood</persName> and The Center for Textual Studies and Digital Humanities</publisher>
        <availability>
          <p>Reproduced by digitized version from Archive.org, contributed by <name>Cornell University Library</name>. There are no known
            copyright restrictions in the United States on the use of the texts. More information on rights issues associated with public
            domain texts can be found at https://www.library.cornell.edu/about/policies/public-domain</p>
          <p>This text may be freely distributed for personal use, research, and teaching (including distribution to classes) as long as
            this statement of availability is included in the text. It may be linked to freely in Internet editions of all kinds.</p>
          <p>Scholars interested in changing or adding to these texts (for example, creating a new edition or adding additional markup) may
            do so.</p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      
      <sourceDesc>
        
        <bibl>
          <title>The Picayune's Creole Cook Book</title>
          <publisher>New Orleans, La., The Picayune</publisher>
          <date>1910</date>
          <edition>4th</edition>
          <sponsor>Cornell University Library</sponsor>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <p>This editions provides editorial notes</p>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Page breaks and column breaks have been preserved whenever possible. Abbreviations and spellings have been maintained. Line breaks
          have not been encoded. All presentational elements such as alignments, all caps, bold, and italics will be encoded.</p>
        <normalization method="silent">
          <p>Typos have been maintained</p>
        </normalization>
        <hyphenation eol="none">
          <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of columns or lines have been reformed</p>
        </hyphenation>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <!-- Add date, initials, and what the change was -->
      <change when="2020-10-26" who="EAH">Created header and test template</change>
      <change when="2020-11-2" who="RH">Added transcription to template and began encoding</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>

<pb n="156"/>
  <div type="chapter">
    <head rend="align(center) case(allcaps)"> Chapter XXII.</head>
    <head type="main" rend="bold">SALADS.</head>
    <head type="sub"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Des Salades.</foreign></head>
  <!-- column 1 -->
    <cb n="1"/>
    <div type="orientationNote">
      <p>
        The Creoles have always been famous for the excellent salads which grace their tables.
        Salads, like soup, or gumbo, is the daily accompaniment of dinner in even the most humble <name>Creole</name> home.
        They hold, one and all, that a good salad is a most delightful dish, but a poor one is worse than none at all.
      </p>
      <p>
        The old Spanish proverb that “to make a perfect salad there should be a miser for vinegar, a spendthrift for oil, a wise man for salt, and a
<!-- column 2 -->
  <cb n="2"/>
        madcap to stir all these ingredients, and mix them well together,” still holds as the unfailing <name>Creole</name> rule in making a good salad.
        The reason is clear.
        For the dressing of the salad should be saturated with the oil, before the salt, pepper and vinegar are added.
        Results have proven however, where the salad is dressed in the bowl, that there can never really be too much vinegar, for, from the specific gravity of vinegar, compared to the oil, what is useless will

<pb n="157"/>
<!--column 1-->
  <cb n="1"/>
        fall to the bottom of the bowl.
        By dissolving the salt in the vinegar, instead of the oil, too it becomes more thoroughly distributed throughout the salad.
        But this will not hold where each makes his own salad dressing at tables, as is common in <name>Creole</name> families.
      </p>
        <!--unclear which French Dressing is being referred to here-->
      <p>
        The simple French Dressing for salads is always the best for daily use, and also for formal dinner.
        It is not only lighter, as compared to the <div type="recipe_addition” corresp=“#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise Dressing</div>, and therefore, far more acceptable at dinners where the courses are many, but the <name>Creoles</name> hold, like the <name>French</name>, that it is the only dressing for salads that are not intended for luncheons or teas, such as chicken, shrimp or crab salads.
        A <div type="recipe_addition” corresp=“#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise Dressing</div> for salad should never be used at the family dinner or formal dinings.
      </p>
      <p>
        A meat salad is never an economical article of food, if one counts all the items of cost.
        The wretched combinations, too, which pass for Mayonnaise, and which are nothing more than a paste spread over the top of the salad, or stirred through with a mixture of pepper, vinegar and salt, cannot be too greatly condemned.
        The making of a good <div type="recipe_addition” corresp=“#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise</div> is a matter of art, and requires the skill that comes from experience.
        Practice will teach that there is no need for useless expenditure of time in making this dressing, and that once you have learned the simple trick of securing the good start in the way of blending, or rather “working,” the oil into the egg, drop by drop, the task of making a fine <div type="recipe_addition” corresp=“#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing"><foreign xml:id="fr">Sauce à la Mayonnaise</foreign></div>, becomes a very simple and easy one.
        The <div type="recipe_addition” corresp=“#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise</div>, which is intended, as stated above, only for meat dressings, and the French Salad Dressing are the only two in general use in <name>Creole</name> households.
      </p>
      <p>
        The <name>Creoles</name> serve salads for breakfast, luncheon and dinners, while no elegant supper is considered complete without a salad.
        The ancient <name>Creole</name> dames have always declared that for health the green salad, with the simple French Dressing, is the proper one.
        Such a salad is to be found daily on their tables.
        Make the French Dressing according to the directions given in the subjoined recipes, and pour this over the lettuce, with a tablespoonful of parsley, cut very fine, sprinkled over again.
        Salads of this order, are, indeed, the most healthful in the world.
        The old <name>Creoles</name> say that the family that eats much oil will never know a headache, and the medicinal virtues of lettuce and celery are such as are acknowledged by physicians, and all nervous and energetic people require them as sedatives.
        The <name>French</name> say that the <name>Americans</name> eat too much meat, and too little vegetables.
        Happily, the <name>Creoles</name> know how to blend
  <cb n="2"/>
<!-- column 2 -->
        both, and they declare that this accounts for the longevity and good health of the ancient members of the race.
      </p>
    </div>

    <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">
      <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Plain French Dressings for Salads.</head>
      <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Assaisonment Français.</foreign></head>
      <list>
        <item><ingredient type="fat"><measure type="volume" quantity="3" unit="tablespoon" commodity="olive_oil">3 Tablespoonfuls of the Best Olive Oil.</measure></ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="volume" quantity="1" unit="tablespoon" commodity="vinegar">1 Tablespoonful of Vinegar, According to Taste.</measure></ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="amount" quantity="¼" unit="teaspoon" commodity ="salt">¼ Teaspoonful of Salt.</measure></ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="amount" quantity="¼" unit="teaspoon" commodity ="black_pepper">¼ Teaspoonful of Black Pepper.</measure></ingredient></item>
      </list>
      <p>
        First put the <ingredient type="fat">oil</ingredient> into a small bowl.
        Then add gradually the <ingredient type="spice">salt</ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice">pepper</ingredient> until all are thoroughly mixed.
        Then add gradually the <ingredient type="spice">vinegar</ingredient>, stirring continually for about a minute.
        It is now ready to pour over the salad, and remember that it must be mixed thoroughly.
        The proportion of vinegar varies according to the salad to be dressed.
        <div type="recipe_addition” corresp=“#pic22.28_lettuce_salad">Lettuce salad</div> requires but little; <div type="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic22.33_tomato_salad">tomato salad</div>, <div type="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic22.21_corn_salad">corn salad</div> or <foreign xml:id="fr">Doucette</foreign> requires more.
        Serve this dressing with <ingredient type="vegetable">lettuce</ingredient>, <ingredient type="fruits">tomato</ingredient>, <ingredient type="vegetable">onion</ingredient>, <ingredient type="vegetable">cucumber</ingredient> and other vegetables and green salads.
      </p>
    </div>

    <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.2_french_dressing_2">
      <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">French Dressing No. 2.</head>
      <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Assaisonment Français.</foreign></head>
      <list>
        <item><ingredient type="fat"><measure type="volume" quantity="3" unit="tablespoon" commodity="oil">3 Tablespoonfuls of Oil.</measure></ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="volume" quantity="1" unit="tablespoon" commodity="tarragon_vinegar">1 Tablespoonful of Tarragon Vinegar</measure></ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="saltspoon" commodity="black_pepper">A Saltspoon Each of Black Pepper</measure></ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="saltspoon" commodity="salt">Salt.</measure></ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient type="vegetable"><measure type="item" commodity="onion">Chopped Onion</measure></ingredient>and<ingredient type="herb"><measure type="item" commodity="parsley">Parsley</measure></ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient type="vegetable">The Juice of Half an Onion.</ingredient></item>
      </list>
      <p>
        Mix these in the order given above, adding the <ingredient type="vegetable">onion juice</ingredient> and <ingredient type="herb">parsley</ingredient>, well chopped, last.
        This is a more elaborate French dressing.
        Serve with the same salads as above.
        The <ingredient type="fat">oil</ingredient> may be omitted for those who do not like it, but it will be no longer in either of these recipes a French Dressing.
        The <name>Creoles</name> hold that the oil is a very healthy, digestible and essential ingredient.
      </p>
    </div>

    <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.3_mustard_dressing">
      <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Mustard Dressing.</head>
      <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Assaisonment à la Moutarde.</foreign></head>
      <list>
        <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="volume" quantity="1" unit="tablespoon" commodity="vinegar">1 Tablespoonful of Vinegar</measure></ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="volume" quantity="1" unit="teaspoon" commodity="mustard">1 Teaspoonful of Prepared Mustard</measure></ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient type="fat"><measure type="volume" quantity="2" unit="tablespoon" commodity="olive_oil">2 Tablespoonfuls of Olive Oil.</measure></ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient type="eggs"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="item" commodity="egg">The Yolk of 1 Egg, if Desired.</measure></ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient type="spice">Salt</ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice">Pepper</ingredient> to Taste.</item>
      </list>
      <p>
        Blend the <ingredient type="spice">mustard</ingredient> and the <ingredient type="fat">oil</ingredient>, adding the latter, drop by drop at first, and then proceeding more confidently.
        Whenever the dressing appears to be curdling, add a few drops of <ingredient type="spice">vinegar</ingredient>, and work rapidly till it becomes smooth again.
        Add the <ingredient type="spice">salt</ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice">pepper</ingredient>, and when the dressing is finished, use it for <div type="recipe_addition” corresp=“#pic22.14_celery_salad">celery salad</div>, <ingredient type="fish">fish</ingredient>, <ingredient type="fruits">tomatoes</ingredient>, <ingredient type="vegetable">potatoes</ingredient>, etc.
        If the oil appears to separate from the other ingredients, it can always be rubbed into them smoothly again by adding a few drops of vinegar.
        In all these salads the question of oil and its measurements can only be approximated.
        Good judgment must always be the final test.
      </p>
    </div>

<pb n="158"/>
  <cb n="1"/>
<!-- column 1 -->
  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.4_creole_french_dressing">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Creole French Dressing.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Assaisonment à la Créole.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="fat"><measure type="volume" quantity="3" unit="tablespoon" commodity="olive_oil">3 Tablespoonfuls of the Best Olive Oil.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="volume" quantity="1" unit="tablespoon" commodity="vinegar">1 Tablespoonful of Vinegar.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="volume" quantity="1" unit="teaspoon" commodity="mustard">1 Teaspoonful of Prepared Mustard</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="eggs"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="item" commodity="egg">The Yolk of a Hard-Boiled Egg.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="spice">Salt</ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice">Pepper</ingredient> to Taste.</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      Blend the <ingredient type="fat">oil</ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice">salt</ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice">pepper</ingredient> in the manner above indicated, and then add these to the <ingredient type="spice">mustard</ingredient> drop by drop, alternating with the <ingredient type="spice">vinegar</ingredient>.
      When well blended add the well-mashed <ingredient type="egg">yolk of a hard-boiled egg</ingredient>.
      Stir well, and serve with <div type="recipe_addition” corresp=“#pic22.28_lettuce_salad">lettuce</div>, <div type="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic22.14_celery_salad">celery</div> or <div type="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic22.39_potato_salad">potato salad</div>.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Mayonnaise Dressing.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Sauce Mayonnaise.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="eggs"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="item" commodity="egg">Yolk of 1 Egg.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="fat">Sweet Oil.</ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="fruits">Lemon.</ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="spice">Vinegar.</ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="spice">Pepper</ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice">Salt.</ingredient></item>
    </list>
    <p>
      Take the <ingredient type="eggs">yolk of one fresh egg</ingredient>, raw, and put it in a bowl.
      The egg and the <ingredient type="fat">oil</ingredient> must be cold, and in summer it is well to keep the soup plate in which you make the dressing on cracked ice in a pan, so that the oil will not run.
      Put the yolk in a plate; add, drop by drop, a little sweet oil from the bottle.
      When you have dropped about a spoonful being careful to work it into the yolk of the egg drop by drop and blend all the time, take a <ingredient type="fruits">lemon</ingredient> and drop a few drops into the mixture.
      It will at once begin to harden as you stir it in.
      Continue stirring till the egg grows hard, and then steadily, drop by drop, let the oil fall, working it all the time with your fork into the egg.
      Have another spoon, begin to drop in the lemon juice, working it the same way again till it hardens the egg.
      Then begin again with the oil and work again, and again drop the lemon till you have the juice of half a lemon and about <measure type="volume" quantity="2" unit="gills" commodity="oil">two gills of oil</measure>, finishing with the oil.
      When the egg begins to curdle, add a little salt, but do not add this salt till the Mayonnaise is complete.
      Serve very cold, with salads, etc.
      Mayonnaise is the standing sauce for <div type="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic22.16_chicken_salad">chicken salad</div>, <div type="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic22.42_shrimp_salad">shrimp salad</div>, <div type="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic22.18_crab_salad_à_la_mayonnaise">crab salad</div>, etc.
      When making for these large salads, as a garnish use <measure type="amount" quantity="3" unit="item" commodity="egg">three yolks of eggs</measure> and other ingredients in proportion.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.6_rémoulade_dressing">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Rémoulade Dressing.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Sauce Rémoulade.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="eggs"><measure type="amount" quantity="3" unit="item" commodity="egg">3 Hard-Boiled Eggs.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="eggs"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="item" commodity="egg">1 Raw Yolk of Egg.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="volume" quantity="1" unit="tablespoon" commodity="tarragon_vinegar">1 Tablespoonful of Tarragon Vinegar.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="fat"><measure type="volume" quantity="3" unit="tablespoon" commodity="olive_oil">3 Tablespoonfuls of Olive Oil.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="vegetable"><measure type="amount" quantity="½" unit="clove" commodity="garlic">½ Clove of Garlic, Minced Very Fine.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="amount" quantity="½" unit="teaspoon" commodity="mustard">½ Teaspoonful of Prepared Mustard.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="spice">Salt</ingredient>and<ingredient type="spice">Cayenne</ingredient>to taste</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      A Rémoulade is a cold sauce. And is always served with cold meats.
      Boil the <ingredient type="eggs">eggs</ingredient> till hard. Remove the shells and set aside the whites, which you
<!-- column 2-->
  <cb n="2"/>
      will have crumbled fine for a garnish.
      Put the yolks into a bowl, and mash very fine, till perfectly smooth.
      Add the <ingredient type="spice">mustard</ingredient>, and mix well, and the seasonings of <ingredient type="spice">vinegar</ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice">salt</ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice">Cayenne</ingredient> to taste.
      Then add the <ingredient type="fat">olive oil</ingredient>, drop by drop, working in the egg all the time, and then add the yolk of the raw egg, and work in thoroughly, till light.
      Then add the <ingredient type="fruits">juice of half a lemon</ingredient>.
      Mix well, increasing the quantity of oil or vinegar, according to taste, very slightly.
      If the sauce is not thoroughly mixed, it will curdle.
      It is now ready to be served with cold meats, fish or salads.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.7_vinaigrette_dressing">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Vinaigrette Dressing.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Sauce Vinaigrette.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="vegetable"><measure type="amount" quantity="12" unit="item" commodity="shallot">12 Shallots.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="volume" quantity="2" unit="tablespoons" commodity="vinegar">2 Tablespoonfuls of Vinegar.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="fat"><measure type="volume" quantity="5" unit="tablespoons" commodity="oil">5 Tablespoonfuls of Oil.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="herb"><measure type="amount" quantity="2" unit="tablespoons" commodity="parsley">2 Tablespoonfuls of Chopped Parsley.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="spice">Salt</ingredient>and<ingredient type="spice">Pepper</ingredient>to Taste</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      Mix all together, as in a <div type="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic30.56_ravigote_sauce_cold">Sauce Ravigote, cold (see recipe)</div>, and add the <ingredient type="fat">oil</ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice">vinegar</ingredient>;
      serve cold, with cold boiled meat, cold boiled fish, etc.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.8_anchovy_salad">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Anchovy Salad.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade d’Anchois.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="fish"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="box" commodity="anchovy">1 Box of Anchovies.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item>A Plain French Dressing.</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      Cut the <ingredient type="fish">sardines</ingredient> into pieces of about an inch in length.
      Season nicely with a <div type ="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing</div> and serve.
      This is a delicious luncheon dish.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.9_artichoke_salad">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Artichoke Salad.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Artichauts en Salade.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="vegetable"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="pint" commodity="artichoke">1 Pint of Cold Boiled Artichokes.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="volume" quantity="1" unit="teaspoon" commodity="vinegar">1 Teaspoonful of Vinegar</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="herb"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="teaspoon" commodity="parsley">1 Teaspoonful of Chopped Parsley.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item>French Dressing.</item>
    </list>
    <p>
        Boil the <ingredient type="vegetable">Artichokes.</ingredient> <div type="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic29.1_french_artichokes_boiled">(See recipe)</div>.
        When cold, peel them and cut into quarters.
        Add <ingredient type="herb">chopped parsley</ingredient> and the French dressing; mix, and serve very cold.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.10_tips_of_asparagus_salad">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Tips of Asparagus Salad.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Pointes d’Asperges en Salade.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="vegetable"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="pint" commodity="asparagus">1 Pint of Asparagus Tips.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item>A Plain French Dressing.</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      Boil the Asparagus tips. <div type="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic29.8_boiled_asparagus">(See recipe.)</div>
      When cold, place on a dish and garnish nicely.
      Serve very cold, with French Dressing.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.11_bean_salad">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Bean Salad.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade d’Haricots.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="vegetable"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="pint" commodity="beans">1 Pint of Cold Beans.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item>Vinaigrette Sauce.</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      This is a nice way of utilizing cold left-over red or white beans.
      Serve with a Vinaigrette Sauce. <div type =“recipe_addition” corresp=“#pic30.65_vinaigrette_sauce”>(See recipe.)</div>
    </p>
  </div>

<pb n="159"/>
  <cb n="1"/>
  <!--column 1-->
  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.12_beet_salad">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Beet Salad.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Betteraves.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="vegetable"><measure type="amount" quantity="4" unit="item" commodity="red_beets">4 Large Red Beets.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item>French Dressing.</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      Boil the <ingredient type="vegetable">beets</ingredient> till done, and then peel and slice nicely.
      Set them to cool and pour over them a French dressing or a plain dressing of <ingredient type="spice">vinegar</ingredient>, <ingredient type="spice">salt</ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice">pepper.</ingredient>
      This is a nice spring or winter salad in New Orleans.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.13_cauliflower_salad">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Cauliflower Salad.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Chou-fleur à la Vinaigrette.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="vegetable"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="pint" commodity="cauliflower">1 Pint of Boiled Cauliflower.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="herb"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="teaspoon" commodity="parsley">1 Teaspoonful of Chopped Parsley.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="spice"><measure type="volume" quantity="1" unit="teaspoon" commodity="tarragon_vinegar">1 Teaspoonful of Tarragon Vinegar.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item>A French Dressing (plain).</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      Boil the <ingredient type="vegetable">cauliflower</ingredient> as directed. <div type =“recipe_addition” corresp=“#pic29.46_boiled_cauliflower_cream_sauce”>(See recipe.)</div><!--please check number of referenced recipe again-->
      Then separate the flowerets; mix them with <ingredient type="herb">parsley</ingredient>, and cut the remainder very fine and mix also.
      Let it cool.
      Serve with a French dressing, after adding first an extra teaspoonful of <ingredient type="spice">Tarragon vinegar.</ingredient>
      This is a famous and very popular <name>Creole</name> way of serving <ingredient type="vegetable">cauliflower.</ingredient>
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.14_celery_salad">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Celery Salad.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Celeri.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="vegetable"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="pint" commodity="french_celery">1 Pint of Crisp French Celery.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item><ingredient type="eggs"><measure type="amount" quantity="2" unit="item" commodity="egg">2 Hard-Boiled Eggs.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item>French Dressing.</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      Cut the <ingredient type="vegetable">celery</ingredient> into pieces of about a quarter of an inch.
      Chop <ingredient type="eggs"><measure type="amount" quantity="2" unit="item" commodity="egg">two hardboiled eggs</measure></ingredient>, not too fine, and mix well within the <ingredient type="vegetable">chopped celery</ingredient>.
      Blend all with French dressing and serve.
      This is a delicious salad.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.15_celery_mayonnaise">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Celery Mayonnaise.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Mayonnaise de Celeri.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="vegetable"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="pint" commodity="white_celery">1 Pint of Crisp White Celery.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item>A Mayonnaise Sauce.</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      Chop the <ingredient type="vegetable">celery</div>, or rather cut fine, as indicated in the above recipe.
      Mix the <div type="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic30.44_mayonnaise_sauce">Mayonnaise</div><!--to check referenced recipe number again--> with it.
      Garnish nicely with <ingredient type="vegetable">celery tips</ingredient> and serve.
      The <div type="recipe_addition" corresp="#pic22.3_mustard_dressing">mustard dressing</div> is even nicer than the Mayonnaise for this salad.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.16_chervil_salad">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Chervil Salad.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Cerfeuil.</foreign></head>
    <list>
      <item><ingredient type="herb"><measure type="amount" quantity="1" unit="pint" commodity="chervil">1 Pint of Chervil.</measure></ingredient></item>
      <item>A Plain French Dressing.</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      <ingredient type="herb">Chervil</ingredient> is a delicious salad herb, much affected by <name>French</name> and <name>Creole</name> gourmets.
      It is served cut fine between bits, in the same manner as <div type =“recipe_addition” corresp=“#pic22.28_lettuce_salad”>Lettuce Salad,</div> with a French Dressing.
    </p>
  </div>

 <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.17_chicken_salad">
   <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Chicken Salad.</head>
   <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Mayonnaise de Volaille.</foreign></head>
      <list type="ingredientList">
        <item type="poultry">1 Pint of Cold Boiled Chicken.</item>
        <item type="recipe_addition" corres="#pic30.44_mayonnaise_sauce">½ Pint of Mayonnaise Sauce.</item>
        <item type="vegetable">1 Head of Crisp Fresh Lettuce.</item>
      </list>
      <p type="instructions">
        Cut the chicken into small dice.
        Chop half of the lettuce very fine, and season well with <ingredient type="spice">salt and pepper.</ingredient>
        Make a bed of the remainder of the lettuce leaves, and place first a layer


<cb n="2"/>
<!-- column 2 -->
      of the chicken and then of the lettuce, until you have used all.
      Spread the <div type="recipe_addition" corres="#pic30.44_mayonnaise_sauce"> Mayonnaise Sauce</div> over the top nicely, and garnish prettily with slices of cold hard-boiled eggs, sliced beets, celery tips, etc.
        For chicken and celery salad follow the recipe for <div type="recipe_addition">Volaille en Salade</div>, given under the heading of “Poultry.” (See recipe.) <!--Volaille en Salade needs to be referenced here, I think it's on page 119-->
      Left-over chicken may be utilized in either of these salads.
      </p>
 </div>

   <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.18_crab_salad_à_la_mayonnaise">
     <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Crab Salad à la Mayonnaise.</head>
     <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Mayonnaise de Crabes.</foreign></head>
     <list type="ingredientList">
       <item type="seafood">1 Pint of the Meat of Crab (hard shell).</item>
       <item type="recipe_addition" corres="#pic30.44_mayonnaise_sauce">Mayonnaise.</item>
       <item type="egg">Hard-Boiled Eggs.</item>
       <item type="garnish">Garnishes.</item>
     </list>
     <p type="instructions">
       Boil and pick crabs sufficient to give a pint of meat. <div type="recipe_addition">(See recipe for Boiling Crabs.)</div><!--needs recipe ID from recipe for Boiling Crabs-->
       Season well with <ingredient type="spice">salt</ingredient> and <ingredient type="spice">pepper</ingredient>.
       Place in a dish, on a bed of crisp lettuce leaves, spreading over them the Mayonnaise Sauce, and garnish nicely with hard-boiled eggs, sliced beets and tips of celery.
     </p>
   </div>

   <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.19_crawfish_salad">
     <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Mayonnaise d’Écrevisses.</head>
     <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Mayonnaise de Crabes.</foreign></head>
     <list type="ingredientList">
       <item type="seafood">3 Dozen Crawfish.</item>
       <item type="recipe_addition" corres="#pic30.44_mayonnaise_sauce">A Sauce a la Mayonnaise.</item>
     </list>
     <p type="instructions">
       Boil the crawfish, pick the meat out of the shells, heads and tails, break them into pieces, and prepare in exactly the same manner as <name xml:id="pic22.42_shrimp_salad">Shrimp Salad</name>.
     </p>
   </div>

   <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.20_cress_salad">
     <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Cress Salad.</head>
     <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Cresson.</foreign></head>
     <list type="ingredientList">
       <item type="vegetable">Cress.</item>
       <item type="spice">Vinegar.</item>
       <item type="spice">Salt and Pepper.</item>
     </list>
     <p type="instructions">
       Prepare in exactly the same manner as <div type="recipe_addition" corres="">lettuce</div>, washing and bringing to the table firm and crisp. <!--add lettuce ID-->
       In this salad use for dressing only Tarragon vinegar, salt and pepper to taste.
     </p>
   </div>

   <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.21_cucumber_salad">
     <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Cucumber Salad.</head>
     <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Concombres.</foreign></head>
     <list type="ingredientList">
       <item type="vegetable">2 Fine Cucumbers.</item>
       <item>A Plain French Dressing</item>
     </list>
     <p type="instructions">
       Wash and slice two nice young cucumbers, and use a plain dressing of vinegar, salt and pepper.
       This is a very delicious salad.
       There are many so-called elegant novelties introduced lately in the way of serving cucumbers, such as stuffed cucumbers, fried cucumbers, etc.
       The <name>Creoles</name> look with disdain, and justly, on these silly innovations in the serving of a vegetable which nature intended to be used for salad purposes, and nothing else.
     </p>
   </div>

   <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.22_corn_salad">
     <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Corn Salad.</head>
     <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Maches, ou Doucette.</foreign></head>
     <list type="ingredientList">
       <item type="vegetable">1 Pint of Corn Salad</item>
       <item>A Plain French Dressing</item>
     </list>
     <p type="instructions">
       This is an excellent salad, and is prepared and served with a French dressing.
       Take one pint of fresh Doucette and pare off the outer stale


<pb n="160"/>
  <cb n="1"/>
<!--column 1--><!--to check the instructions again-->
      leaves, if there are any; cut off the roots.
      Wash the Doucette well in two waters, drain in a napkin and place in the salad bowl.
      When ready to serve add a plain French dressing but not before.
      Mix well, so that every portion will be impregnated with the dressing.
      Serve very cold.
      A garnish of two hard-boiled eggs, sliced or cut in quarters, or of two medium-sized beets, which may be added both for taste and effect.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.23_dandelion_salad">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Dandelion Salad.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Dent-de-Lion</foreign></head>
    <list type="ingredientList">
      <item type="vegetable">1 Pint of Fresh White Dandelion.</item>
      <item>A Plain French Dressing</item>
    </list>
    <p type="instructions">
      Cut off the roots and green portion of the leaves; wash and steep in salt and water.
      When they become crisp, drain and press dry; rub the salad bowl with <item type="vegetable">a clove of garlic</a> and season the dandelions with French dressing.
      This salad may also be served with two hard-boiled eggs cut in quarters or sliced and laid over; or with two medium-sized beets, sliced, and seasoned with a plain French dressing.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.24_endive_salad">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Endive Salad.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Chicorée.</foreign></head>
    <list type="ingredientList">
      <item type="vegetable">1 Pint of Endives.</item>
      <item>French Dressing</item>
      <item type="herb">1 Teaspoonful of Chervil, Chopped Very Fine.</item>
    </list>
    <p type="instructions">
      Prepare the endives in the same manner as the <div type="recipe_addition" corres="">lettuce</div>.
      When ready to service, add the chervil and the French dressing.
      If endives stand, like lettuce, they will wilt after being dressed. Serve immediately.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.25_fish_salad">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Fish Salad.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Poisson à la Mayonnaise.</foreign></head>
    <list type="ingredientList">
      <item type="fish">1 Pint of Cold Boiled Fish.</item>
      <item type="vegetable">1 Head of Lettuce.</item>
      <item type="recipe_addition" corres="#pic30.44_mayonnaise_sauce">Mayonnaise Sauce.</item>
    </list>
    <p type="instructions">
      Use cold boiled left-over fish, picking nicely into bits of about an inch and a half square.
      Follow the same directions as in the above recipes, only do not mix lettuce and fish in layers.
      There is nothing nicer than a fine fish salad.
    </p>
  </div>

  <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.26_green_pepper_salad">
    <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Green Pepper Salad.</head>
    <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Piments Doux à la Créole.</foreign></head>
    <list type="ingredientList">
      <item type="vegetable">4 Tomatoes.</item>
      <item type="vegetable">2 Green Peppers.</item>
      <item type="vegetable">1 Large Onion.</item>
      <item type="recipe_addition" corres="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing, Plain.</item>
    </list>
    <p type="instructions">
      Slice the tomatoes, onions and green peppers nicely and thin, arrange on a dish, placing a layer of tomatoes, an alternate layer of onion and green pepper, and tomatoes mixed.
      Dress either before bringing to the table, or at the table, with French dressing.
      This is a great <name>Creole</name> family salad, and a very healthy one.
    </p>
  </div>

<!--column 2-->
<cb n="2"/>
    <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.27_green_peppers_à_l’Espgnole">
      <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Green Peppers à l’Espgnole.</head> <!--What does à l’Espgnole mean?-->
      <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Piments Verts en Salade à l’Espagnole.</foreign></head>
      <list type="ingredientList">
        <item type="vegetable">6 Green Peppers.</item>
        <item type="vegetable">3 Tomatoes.</item>
        <item type="recipe_addition" corres="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing.</item>
      </list>
      <p type="instructions">
        Parboil the peppers so that they will peel easily, and scald the tomatoes.
        Peel them, removing the seeds of the peppers.
        Cut the peppers into one-inch pieces, slice the tomatoes, and serve with plain French dressing as a salad.
      </p>
    </div>

    <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.28_lentil_salad">
      <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Lentil Salad.</head>
      <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Lentilles.</foreign></head>
      <list type="ingredientList">
        <item type="legume">1 Pint of Lentils.</item>
        <item type="recipe_addition" corres="#pic22.7_vinaigrette_dressing">A Vinaigrette Sauce (See Recipe).</item><!--to check if this is the right ID-->
      </list>
      <p type="instructions">
        Lentils are prepared in the same manner as <div type="recipe_addition" corres="#pic22.11_bean_salad">Bean Salad (see recipe)</div>, and served with Vinaigrette Sauce.
        They make a cheap, excellent and healthy salad.
      </p>
    </div>

    <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.29_lettuce_salad">
      <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Lettuce Salad.</head>
      <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Laitue.</foreign></head>
      <list type="ingredientList">
        <item type="vegetable">3 Heads of Lettuce.</item>
        <item type="recipe_addition">French Dressing.</item><!--to check if this is the right ID-->
        <item type="egg">2 Eggs.</item>
      </list>
      <p type="instructions">
        Take fresh, crisp lettuce of sufficient quantity for the number to be served, three young heads being enough for six.
        Dip in cold water examining each leaf, and pick over carefully, and select the fresh crisp leaves.
        Place all these in a salad bowl, and garnish nicely with sliced hard-boiled egg.
        Never dress the lettuce before bringing to the table.
        The vinegar causes the leaves to wilt utterly, and takes away all the relish which one experiences from looking at a fresh, crisp dish, and also spoils a fine table garnish.
        Bring to the table, and let the sauce, always a plain French dressing or Creole dressing preferred, be made at the table.
        Generally each makes the dressing to suit himself or herself, using proportions of greater or lesser quantity than those mentioned in the recipe.
        If one person dresses the salad for the table, use the proportions given above in any of the French salad dressings for this amount of lettuce.
        This is one of the nicest and most refreshing as well as one of the healthiest of all salads.
      </p>
    </div>

    <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.30_louisiana_salad">
      <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Louisiana Salad.</head>
      <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade Louisianaise.</foreign></head>
      <list type="ingredientList">
        <item type="vegetable">2 Lettuce Heads.</item>
        <item type="vegetable">6 Pickled Cucumbers.</item>
        <item type="vegetable">2 Dozen Pickled Onions.</item>
        <item type="recipe_addition" corres="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing.</item>
      </list>
      <p type="instructions">
        Use, in this fancy salad, lettuce, pickled cucumbers, pickled onions, cut in dice, and serve with a French dressing.
      </p>
    </div>

    <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.31_okra_salad">
      <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Okra Salad.</head>
      <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Fevi.</foreign></head>
      <list type="ingredientList">
        <item><ingredient type="vegetable">4 Dozen Boiled Young Okras.</ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient>French Dressing.</ingredient></item>
      </list>
      <p type="instructions">
        Boil the okra as directed. <item div type="recipe_addition">(See recipe.)</div> When cold, dress nicely with
        <!--to add recipe ID for boiled okra-->

<pb n="161"/>
<cb n="1"/>
<!--column 1-->
        vinegar, salt and pepper, or, if preferred, the plain French dressing, and serve very cold. 
        This is a most delightful summer salad, the okra being very cooling in our tropical climate.
      </p>
    </div>
      
      <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.32_spanish_salad">
        <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Spanish Salad.</head>
        <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade à l’Espagnole.</foreign></head>
        <list type="ingredientList">
          <item><ingredient type="vegetable">4 Sliced Tomatoes.</ingredient></item>
          <item><ingredient type="vegetable">2 Dozen Pickled Onions.</ingredient></item>
          <item><ingredient corres="#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">½ Pint of Mayonnaise Dressing.</ingredient></item>
        </list>
        <p type="instructions">
          This is a very much affected salad, made of sliced tomatoes and pickled onions, <!--what is an affected salad? Fancy?-->
          prettily arranged around a small bed of Mayonnaise heaped in the center.
        </p>
      </div>

      <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.33_string_bean_salad">
        <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">String Bean Salad.</head>
        <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Haricots Verts en Salade.</foreign></head>
        <list type="ingredientList">
          <item><ingredient type="vegetable">1 Pint of Cold Boiled String Beans.</ingredient></item>
          <item><ingredient corres="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing (plain).</ingredient></item>
        </list>
        <p type="instructions">
          Only very young and tender beans should be used for this salad. 
          Boil as directed under the heading “Vegetables” and put the beans in a salad bowl and allow to cool well. <!--to add recipe ID-->
          Serve with a plain French dressing of vinegar and a dash of Cayenne.
        </p>
      </div>

    <div type ="recipe" xml:id="pic22.34_tomato_salad">
      <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Tomato Salad.</head>
      <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Tomates.</foreign></head>
      <list type="ingredientList">
        <item><ingredient type="vegetable">4 Fresh Fine Tomatoes.</ingredient></item>
        <item><ingredient corres="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing.</ingredient></item>
      </list>
      <p type="instructions">
        Slice the tomatoes nicely and place on a salad dish. 
        Never peel or scald tomatoes intended for salad. 
        Serve nicely with a plain French dressing or any of the above dressings. 
        Tomatoes may also be served with Mayonnaise dressing. 
        In this case place them on a bed of crisp, fresh lettuce, whole, and serve one to each person, or cut them in halves. 
        Tomatoes with Mayonnaise is a luncheon dish, or a supper dish.
      </p>
    </div>



Iced Tomatoes.
Tomates Frappé.
6 Whole Tomatoes.
1 Pint Mayonnaise Sauce.
A Garnish of Chopped Ice.
Take the tomatoes whole. Lay on a bed of lettuce or cress, as indicated above. Garnish with chopped ice, and serve very cold with Mayonnaise Sauce. This is delicious and very elegant.

Tomato, Green Pepper and Onion Salad.
Salade à la Créole.
4 Tomatoes.
2 Green Peppers.
1 Large Onion.
French Dressing, Plain.
Slice the tomatoes, onions and green peppers nicely and thin; arrange on a dish, placing a layer of tomatoes, an alternate layer of onion and green pepper, and tomatoes mixed. Dress either before bringing to the table, or at the table, with French dressing. This is a great family salad among the Creoles, and a very
<!-- column 2-->
healthy one. The Creoles follow the old adage, that the taste of the onion must only lurk within the bowl when using it for salad. More than this renders the salad disagreeable and coarse.

Watercress Salad.
Salade de Cresson.
1 Pint of Watercress.
Minced Potato, if desired.
A Plain French Dressing.
This salad is made of watercress simply, or watercress and minced potatoes, mixed in equal quantities, and served with a French dressing. It is a most healthy, light and excellent salad, especially in summer. The salad is delightful without the potatoes. They may be added if desired.

The Gardener’s Wife Salad.
Salade à la Jardiniére.
1 Carrot
3 Beets.
½ Cup of Green Peas.
1 Cup String Beans.
A Plain French Dressing.
Take fine strips of vegetables of different colors, cooked and cold, with green peas and string beans, and dress nicely with oil and Vinegar and serve.

Sardine Salad.
Salade de Sardines.
1 Box Sardines.
A Plain French Dressing.
Cut the sardines into pieces of about half an inch in length. Season nicely with a French dressing and serve. This is a delicious luncheon dish.

Potato Salad.
Salade de Pommes de Terre.
3 Large Cold Boiled Potatoes.
2 Hard-Boiled Eggs.
9 Tablespoonfuls of Olive Oil.
3 Tablespoonfuls of Vinegar.
1 Large Onion.
1 Teaspoonful of Salt.
4 Sprigs of Parsley.
This is a nice way of utilizing cold left-over potatoes. But the freshly boiled potatoes always make the nicest salad. Pare and peel the potatoes, if freshly boiled, and let them cool. Prepare the salad dressing, following implicitly the directions given for plain French dressing, only here the quantities are larger in proportion. Add the vinegar, stirring constantly. A dash of mustard may be added, if desired. Mince the onion very fine, and cut the potatoes into dice or slices, and mix them carefully with the onion. Then add the dressing, turning the potatoes into it without breaking. Sprinkle all with parsley, nicely chopped, and serve cold.
<pb>
<!--column 1-->

Russian Salad.
Salade à la Russe.
2 Carrots.
2 Parsnips.
1 Cup of Cold Minced Fowl.
3 Anchovies.
1 Dozen Olives.
3 Caviares.
1 Tablespoonful of Sauce a la Tartare.
1 Teaspoonful of Mustard.
This salad is made of cooked carrots, parsnips, beets, cold roast beef, cold ham, a truffle (if it can be afforded), all cut into fancy or dice-shaped pieces. Use one ounce of each of the meats, or simply one cup of cold minced fowl, as it may not be convenient to have all these meats at hand in households. Add six boned anchovies and one dozen olives and two caviares, and serve with Tartare Sauce, or with a French salad
<!--column 2-->
dressing, to which mustard has been added. It is a heavy salad.

Shrimp Salad
Salade de Chevrette à la Mayonnaise.
2 Pints of Cold Boiled Shrimp.
1 Head of Crisp Lettuce.
Mayonnaise Sauce.
Take Lake Shrimp and River Shrimp combined, if you have them. Cut the larger Lake Shrimp into two. Season well with salt and pepper. Chop some lettuce. Season well. Place first a layer of shrimp and then of lettuce, and spread over all a Mayonnaise Sauce. Garnish nicely with sliced hard-boiled eggs, sliced beets and celery and lettuce tips, and serve very cold.
