<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lizziehop/reading-cookbooks/main/reading-cookbooks%20TEI/cookbook.odd.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>CHAPTER XXII. SALADS. </title>
        <!-- Supply the title of chapter -->
        <title type="chapter" xml:lang="en"/>
        <sponsor>Center for Textual Studies and Digital Humanities, Loyola University
          Chicago</sponsor>
        <principal>
          <persName>Elizabeth Hopwood</persName>
        </principal>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Transcription by</resp>
          <persName>Elizabeth Hopwood</persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>First round encoding by</resp>
          <persName>Regina Hong</persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Second round encoding by</resp>
          <persName>
            <!-- insert name --></persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Proofreading by</resp>
          <persName>
            <!-- insert name --></persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Editorial research by</resp>
          <persName>
            <!-- insert name --></persName>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>

      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>Reading Cookbooks Project</authority>
        <publisher><persName>Elizabeth Hopwood</persName> and The Center for Textual Studies and
          Digital Humanities</publisher>
        <availability>
          <p>Reproduced by digitized version from Archive.org, contributed by <name>Cornell
              University Library</name>. There are no known copyright restrictions in the United
            States on the use of the texts. More information on rights issues associated with public
            domain texts can be found at
            https://www.library.cornell.edu/about/policies/public-domain</p>
          <p>This text may be freely distributed for personal use, research, and teaching (including
            distribution to classes) as long as this statement of availability is included in the
            text. It may be linked to freely in Internet editions of all kinds.</p>
          <p>Scholars interested in changing or adding to these texts (for example, creating a new
            edition or adding additional markup) may do so.</p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>

      <sourceDesc>

        <bibl>
          <title>The Picayune's Creole Cook Book</title>
          <publisher>New Orleans, La., The Picayune</publisher>
          <date>1910</date>
          <edition>4th</edition>
          <sponsor>Cornell University Library</sponsor>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <p>This editions provides editorial notes</p>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Page breaks and column breaks have been preserved whenever possible. Abbreviations and
          spellings have been maintained. Line breaks have not been encoded. All presentational
          elements such as alignments, all caps, bold, and italics will be encoded.</p>
        <normalization method="silent">
          <p>Typos have been maintained</p>
        </normalization>
        <hyphenation eol="none">
          <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of columns or lines have been reformed</p>
        </hyphenation>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <!-- Add date, initials, and what the change was -->
      <change when="2020-10-26" who="EAH">Created header and test template</change>
      <change when="2020-11-2" who="RH">Added transcription to template and began encoding</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="chapter">
        <pb n="156"/>
        <head rend="align(center) case(allcaps)"> Chapter XXII.</head>
        <head type="main" rend="bold">SALADS.</head>
        <head type="sub">
          <foreign xml:lang="fr">Des Salades.</foreign>
        </head>
        <!-- column 1 -->
        <cb n="1"/>
        <div type="prefatory">
          <p> The Creoles have always been famous for the excellent salads which grace their tables.
            Salads, like soup, or gumbo, is the daily accompaniment of dinner in even the most
            humble <name>Creole</name> home. They hold, one and all, that a good salad is a most
            delightful dish, but a poor one is worse than none at all. </p>
          <p> The old Spanish proverb that “to make a perfect salad there should be a miser for
            vinegar, a spendthrift for oil, a wise man for salt, and a <!-- column 2 -->
            <cb n="2"/> madcap to stir all these ingredients, and mix them well together,” still
            holds as the unfailing <name>Creole</name> rule in making a good salad. The reason is
            clear. For the dressing of the salad should be saturated with the oil, before the salt,
            pepper and vinegar are added. Results have proven however, where the salad is dressed in
            the bowl, that there can never really be too much vinegar, for, from the specific
            gravity of vinegar, compared to the oil, what is useless will <pb n="157"/>
            <!--column 1-->
            <cb n="1"/> fall to the bottom of the bowl. By dissolving the salt in the vinegar,
            instead of the oil, too it becomes more thoroughly distributed throughout the salad. But
            this will not hold where each makes his own salad dressing at tables, as is common in
              <name>Creole</name> families. </p>
          <!--unclear which French Dressing is being referred to here-->
          <p> The simple French Dressing for salads is always the best for daily use, and also for
            formal dinner. It is not only lighter, as compared to the <name
              xml:id="pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise Dressing"</name>, and therefore, far
            more acceptable at dinners where the courses are many, but the <name>Creoles</name>
            hold, like the French, that it is the only dressing for salads that are not intended for
            luncheons or teas, such as chicken, shrimp or crab salads. A <name
              xml:id="pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise Dressing</name> for salad should never
            be used at the family dinner or formal dinings. </p>
          <p> A meat salad is never an economical article of food, if one counts all the items of
            cost. The wretched combinations, too, which pass for Mayonnaise, and which are nothing
            more than a paste spread over the top of the salad, or stirred through with a mixture of
            pepper, vinegar and salt, cannot be too greatly condemned. The making of a good <name
              xml:id="#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise</name> is a matter of art, and
            requires the skill that comes from experience. Practice will teach that there is no need
            for useless expenditure of time in making this dressing, and that once you have learned
            the simple trick of securing the good start in the way of blending, or rather “working,”
            the oil into the egg, drop by drop, the task of making a fine <name
              xml:id="#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing"><foreign xml:id="fr">Sauce à la
                Mayonnaise</foreign></name>, becomes a very simple and easy one. The <name
              xml:id="#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise</name>, which is intended, as stated
            above, only for meat dressings, and the <name
              xml:id="pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Salad Dressing</name> are
            the only two in general use in <name>Creole</name> households. </p>
          <p> The <name>Creoles</name> serve salads for breakfast, luncheon and dinners, while no
            elegant supper is considered complete without a salad. The ancient <name>Creole</name>
            dames have always declared that for health the green salad, with the simple French
            Dressing, is the proper one. Such a salad is to be found daily on their tables. Make the
            French Dressing according to the directions given in the subjoined recipes, and pour
            this over the lettuce, with a tablespoonful of parsley, cut very fine, sprinkled over
            again. Salads of this order, are, indeed, the most healthful in the world. The old
              <name>Creoles</name> say that the family that eats much oil will never know a
            headache, and the medicinal virtues of lettuce and celery are such as are acknowledged
            by physicians, and all nervous and energetic people require them as sedatives. The
            French say that the Americans eat too much meat, and too little vegetables. Happily, the
              <name>Creoles</name> know how to blend <cb n="2"/>
            <!-- column 2 --> both, and they declare that this accounts for the longevity and good
            health of the ancient members of the race. </p>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Plain French Dressings for Salads.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Assaisonment Français.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>3 Tablespoonfuls of the Best<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">Olive Oil</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Tablespoonful of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Vinegar</ingredient>According to Taste</item>
              <item>¼ Teaspoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="salt">Salt</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>¼ Teaspoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Black Pepper</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> First put the oil into a small bowl. Then add gradually the salt and pepper until
              all are thoroughly mixed. Then add gradually the vinegar, stirring continually for
              about a minute. It is now ready to pour over the salad, and remember that it must be
              mixed thoroughly. The proportion of vinegar varies according to the salad to be
              dressed. <name xml:id="#pic22.28_lettuce_salad">Lettuce salad</name> requires but
              little; <name correspp="#pic22.33_tomato_salad">tomato salad</name>, <name
                correspp="#pic22.21_corn_salad">corn salad</name> or <foreign xml:id="fr"
                >Doucette</foreign> requires more. Serve this dressing with lettuce, tomato, onion,
              cucumber and other vegetables and green salads. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.2_french_dressing_2">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">French Dressing No. 2.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Assaisonment Français.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>3 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient class="fat">Oil</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Tablespoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Tarragon Vinegar</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>A Saltspoon Each of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Black Pepper</ingredient> and <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0"
                  class="salt">Salt</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>Chopped<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable"
                  >Onion</ingredient>and<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb"
                  >Parsley</ingredient></item>
              <item>
                <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">The Juice of Half an Onion</ingredient>.
              </item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Mix these in the order given above, adding the onion juice and parsley, well
              chopped, last. This is a more elaborate French dressing. Serve with the same salads as
              above. The oil may be omitted for those who do not like it, but it will be no longer
              in either of these recipes a French Dressing. The <name>Creoles</name> hold that the
              oil is a very healthy, digestible and essential ingredient. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.3_mustard_dressing">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Mustard Dressing.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Assaisonment à la Moutarde.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Tablespoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Vinegar</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Teaspoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="condiment">Prepared Mustard</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>2 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">Olive Oil</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">The Yolk of 1 Egg</ingredient>, if Desired.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Salt</ingredient>
                and <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice"
                  >Pepper</ingredient> to Taste.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Blend the mustard and the oil, adding the latter, drop by drop at first, and then
              proceeding more confidently. Whenever the dressing appears to be curdling, add a few
              drops of vinegar, and work rapidly till it becomes smooth again. Add the salt and
              pepper, and when the dressing is finished, use it for <name
                xml:id="pic22.14_celery_salad">celery salad</name>, fish, tomatoes, potatoes, etc.
              If the oil appears to separate from the other ingredients, it can always be rubbed
              into them smoothly again by adding a few drops of vinegar. In all these salads the
              question of oil and its measurements can only be approximated. Good judgment must
              always be the final test. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <pb n="158"/>
        <cb n="1"/>
        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.4_creole_french_dressing">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Creole French Dressing.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)"><foreign xml:lang="fr">Assaisonment à la Créole.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>3 Tablespoonfuls of the Best <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">Olive Oil</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Tablespoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Vinegar</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Teaspoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="condiment">Prepared Mustard</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">The Yolk of a Hard-Boiled Egg</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="salt">Salt</ingredient>
                and <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Pepper</ingredient> to Taste.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Blend the oil and salt and pepper in the manner above indicated, and then add these
              to the mustard drop by drop, alternating with the vinegar. When well blended add the
              well-mashed yolk of a hard-boiled egg. Stir well, and serve with <name
                xml:id="pic22.28_lettuce_salad">lettuce</name>, <name xml:id="pic22.14_celery_salad"
                >celery</name> or <name xml:id="pic22.39_potato_salad">potato salad</name>. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Mayonnaise Dressing.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sauce Mayonnaise.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">Yolk of 1 Egg</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">Sweet Oil</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Lemon</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Vinegar</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Pepper</ingredient> and <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0"
                  class="salt">Salt</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Take the yolk of one fresh egg, raw, and put it in a bowl. The egg and the oil must
              be cold, and in summer it is well to keep the soup plate in which you make the
              dressing on cracked ice in a pan, so that the oil will not run. Put the yolk in a
              plate; add, drop by drop, a little sweet oil from the bottle. When you have dropped
              about a spoonful being careful to work it into the yolk of the egg drop by drop and
              blend all the time, take a lemon and drop a few drops into the mixture. It will at
              once begin to harden as you stir it in. Continue stirring till the egg grows hard, and
              then steadily, drop by drop, let the oil fall, working it all the time with your fork
              into the egg. Have another spoon, begin to drop in the lemon juice, working it the
              same way again till it hardens the egg. Then begin again with the oil and work again,
              and again drop the lemon till you have the juice of half a lemon and about two gills
              of oil, finishing with the oil. When the egg begins to curdle, add a little salt, but
              do not add this salt till the Mayonnaise is complete. Serve very cold, with salads,
              etc. Mayonnaise is the standing sauce for <name xml:id="pic22.16_chicken_salad"
                >chicken salad</name>, <name xml:id="pic22.42_shrimp_salad">shrimp salad</name>,
                <name xml:id="pic22.18_crab_salad_à_la_mayonnaise">crab salad</name>, etc. When
              making for these large salads, as a garnish use three yolks of eggs and other
              ingredients in proportion. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.6_rémoulade_dressing">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Rémoulade Dressing.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sauce Rémoulade.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>3 Hard-Boiled<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">Eggs</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Raw<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">Yolk of Egg</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Tablespoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Tarragon Vinegar</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>3 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">Olive Oil</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>½ Clove of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="aromatic">Garlic</ingredient>,Minced Very Fine.</item>
              <item>½ Teaspoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="condiment">Prepared Mustard</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="salt"
                  >Salt</ingredient>and<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice"
                  >Cayenne</ingredient>to taste</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> A Rémoulade is a cold sauce. And is always served with cold meats. Boil the eggs
              till hard. Remove the shells and set aside the whites, which you <!-- column 2-->
              <cb n="2"/> will have crumbled fine for a garnish. Put the yolks into a bowl, and mash
              very fine, till perfectly smooth. Add the mustard, and mix well, and the seasonings of
              vinegar and salt and Cayenne to taste. Then add the olive oil, drop by drop, working
              in the egg all the time, and then add the yolk of the raw egg, and work in thoroughly,
              till light. Then add the <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0"
                class="fruit juice">juice of half a lemon</ingredient>. Mix well, increasing the
              quantity of oil or vinegar, according to taste, very slightly. If the sauce is not
              thoroughly mixed, it will curdle. It is now ready to be served with cold meats, fish
              or salads. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.7_vinaigrette_dressing">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Vinaigrette Dressing.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Sauce Vinaigrette.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>12<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Shallots</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>2 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Vinegar</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>5 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">Oil</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>2 Tablespoonfuls of Chopped <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Parsley</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="salt">Salt</ingredient>and<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice"
                  >Pepper</ingredient>to Taste</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Mix all together, as in a Sauce Ravigote, cold <ptr
                target="#pic30.56_ravigote_sauce_cold">(see recipe)</ptr>, and add the oil and
              vinegar; serve cold, with cold boiled meat, cold boiled fish, etc. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.8_anchovy_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Anchovy Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade d’Anchois.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Box of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Anchovies</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Cut the sardines into pieces of about an inch in length. Season nicely with a French
              Dressing and serve. This is a delicious luncheon dish. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.9_artichoke_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Artichoke Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Artichauts en Salade.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of Cold Boiled<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Artichokes</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Teaspoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Vinegar</ingredient></item>
              <item>1 Teaspoonful of Chopped<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Parsley</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Boil the Artichokes.<ptr correspp="#pic29.1_french_artichokes_boiled">(See
                recipe)</ptr>. When cold, peel them and cut into quarters. Add chopped parsley and
              the French dressing; mix, and serve very cold. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.10_tips_of_asparagus_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Tips of Asparagus Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Pointes d’Asperges en Salade.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Asparagus Tips</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Boil the Asparagus tips. <ptr target="#pic29.8_boiled_asparagus">(See recipe.)</ptr>
              When cold, place on a dish and garnish nicely. Serve very cold, with <name
                xml:id="pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing.</name>
            </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.11_bean_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Bean Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade d’Haricots.</foreign>
          </head>
          <list>
            <item>1 Pint of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="legume">Cold Beans</ingredient>.</item>
            <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic30.65_vinaigrette_sauce">Vinaigrette Sauce</ingredient>.</item>
          </list>
          <p> This is a nice way of utilizing cold left-over red or white beans. Serve with a
            Vinaigrette Sauce.<ptr target="#pic30.65_vinaigrette_sauce">(See recipe.)</ptr>
          </p>
        </div>

        <pb n="159"/>
        <cb n="1"/>
        <!--column 1-->
        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.12_beet_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Beet Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Betteraves.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>4 Large<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Red Beets</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Boil the beets till done, and then peel and slice nicely. Set them to cool and pour
              over them a French dressing or a plain dressing of vinegar, salt and pepper. This is a
              nice spring or winter salad in New Orleans. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.13_cauliflower_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Cauliflower Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Chou-fleur à la Vinaigrette.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of Boiled<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Cauliflower</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Teaspoonful of Chopped<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Parsley</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Teaspoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Tarragon Vinegar</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A French Dressing (plain)</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Boil the cauliflower as directed.<ptr
                target="#pic29.46_boiled_cauliflower_cream_sauce">(See
              recipe.)</ptr><!--please check number of referenced recipe again--> Then separate the
              flowerets; mix them with parsley, and cut the remainder very fine and mix also. Let it
              cool. Serve with a French dressing, after adding first an extra teaspoonful of
              Tarragon vinegar. This is a famous and very popular <name>Creole</name> way of serving
              cauliflower. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.14_celery_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Celery Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Celeri.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of Crisp<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">French Celery</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>2 Hard-Boiled<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">Eggs</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing</ingredient>.
              </item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Cut the celery into pieces of about a quarter of an inch. Chop two hardboiled eggs,
              not too fine, and mix well within the chopped celery. Blend all with French dressing
              and serve. This is a delicious salad. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.15_celery_mayonnaise">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Celery Mayonnaise.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Mayonnaise de Celeri.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of Crisp<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">White Celery</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">A Mayonnaise Sauce</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Chop the celery, or rather cut fine, as indicated in the above recipe. Mix the
              Mayonnaise with it. Garnish nicely with celery tips and serve. The <name
                xml:id="pic22.3_mustard_dressing">mustard dressing</name> is even nicer than the
              Mayonnaise for this salad. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.16_chervil_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Chervil Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Cerfeuil.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Chervil</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Chervil is a delicious salad herb, much affected by French and <name>Creole</name>
              gourmets. It is served cut fine between bits, in the same manner as <name
                xml:id="pic22.28_lettuce_salad">Lettuce Salad,</name> with a French Dressing. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.17_chicken_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Chicken Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Mayonnaise de Volaille.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of Cold Boiled<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="poultry">Chicken</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>½ Pint of<ingredient corresp="#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise Sauce</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Head of Crisp Fresh<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Lettuce</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Cut the chicken into small dice. Chop half of the lettuce very fine, and season well
              with salt and pepper. Make a bed of the remainder of the lettuce leaves, and place
              first a layer <cb n="2"/>
              <!-- column 2 --> of the chicken and then of the lettuce, until you have used all.
              Spread the Mayonnaise Sauce over the top nicely, and garnish prettily with slices of
              cold hard-boiled eggs, sliced beets, celery tips, etc. For chicken and celery salad
              follow the recipe for <foreign xml:lang="fr">Volaille en Salade</foreign>, given under
              the heading of “Poultry.” <ptr target="#">(See
              recipe.)</ptr><!--xml:idneeded-onp119--> Left-over chicken may be utilized in either
              of these salads. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.18_crab_salad_à_la_mayonnaise">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Crab Salad à la Mayonnaise.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Mayonnaise de Crabes.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of the<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Meat of Crab (hard shell)</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>Hard-Boiled<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">Eggs</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Garnishes</ingredient>.</item>
              <!--RH: class set to vegetable based on context of instructions-->
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Boil and pick crabs sufficient to give a pint of meat. <ptr target="#">(See recipe
                for Boiling Crabs.)</ptr><!--xml:id--> Season well with <ingredient
                xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="salt">salt</ingredient> and <ingredient
                xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">pepper</ingredient>. Place in a
              dish, on a bed of crisp lettuce leaves, spreading over them the Mayonnaise Sauce, and
              garnish nicely with hard-boiled eggs, sliced beets and tips of celery. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.19_crawfish_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Mayonnaise d’Écrevisses.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Mayonnaise de Crabes.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>3 Dozen<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Crawfish</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing"><foreign xml:lang="fr">A Sauce a la Mayonnaise.</foreign></ingredient></item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Boil the crawfish, pick the meat out of the shells, heads and tails, break them into
              pieces, and prepare in exactly the same manner as <ptr target="#pic22.42_shrimp_salad"
                >Shrimp Salad</ptr>. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.20_cress_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Cress Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Cresson.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Cress</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="liquid">Vinegar</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="salt">Salt</ingredient>
                and <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice">Pepper</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Prepare in exactly the same manner as lettuce, washing and bringing to the table
              firm and crisp. <!--add lettuce ID--> In this salad use for dressing only Tarragon
              vinegar, salt and pepper to taste. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.21_cucumber_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Cucumber Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Concombres.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>2 Fine<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Cucumbers</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing</ingredient></item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Wash and slice two nice young cucumbers, and use a plain dressing of vinegar, salt
              and pepper. This is a very delicious salad. There are many so-called elegant novelties
              introduced lately in the way of serving cucumbers, such as stuffed cucumbers, fried
              cucumbers, etc. The <name>Creoles</name> look with disdain, and justly, on these silly
              innovations in the serving of a vegetable which nature intended to be used for salad
              purposes, and nothing else. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.22_corn_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Corn Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Maches, ou Doucette.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Corn Salad</ingredient></item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing</ingredient></item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> This is an excellent salad, and is prepared and served with a French dressing. Take
              one pint of fresh <foreign xml:lang="fr">Doucette</foreign>and pare off the outer
              stale <pb n="160"/>
              <cb n="1"/>
              <!--column 1--><!--to check the instructions again--> leaves, if there are any; cut
              off the roots. Wash the <foreign xml:lang="fr">Doucette</foreign> well in two waters,
              drain in a napkin and place in the salad bowl. When ready to serve add a plain French
              dressing but not before. Mix well, so that every portion will be impregnated with the
              dressing. Serve very cold. A garnish of two hard-boiled eggs, sliced or cut in
              quarters, or of two medium-sized beets, which may be added both for taste and effect.
            </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.23_dandelion_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Dandelion Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Dent-de-Lion</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of Fresh<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">White Dandelion</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing</ingredient></item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Cut off the roots and green portion of the leaves; wash and steep in salt and water.
              When they become crisp, drain and press dry; rub the salad bowl with a clove of
                <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="aromatic">garlic</ingredient> and season the dandelions with French dressing. This salad may
              also be served with two hard-boiled eggs cut in quarters or sliced and laid over; or
              with two medium-sized beets, sliced, and seasoned with a plain French dressing. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.24_endive_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Endive Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Chicorée.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Endives</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Teaspoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="herb">Chervil</ingredient>, Chopped Very Fine.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Prepare the endives in the same manner as the <ptr target="#">lettuce</ptr>. When
              ready to serve, add the chervil and the French dressing. If endives stand, like
              lettuce, they will wilt after being dressed. Serve immediately. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.25_fish_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Fish Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Poisson à la Mayonnaise.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of Cold Boiled <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Fish</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Head of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Lettuce</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise Sauce</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Use cold boiled left-over fish, picking nicely into bits of about an inch and a half
              square. Follow the same directions as in the above recipes, only do not mix lettuce
              and fish in layers. There is nothing nicer than a fine fish salad. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.26_green_pepper_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Green Pepper Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Piments Doux à la Créole.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>4<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Tomatoes</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>2<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Green Peppers</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Large<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Onion</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing,Plain</ingredient>.
              </item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Slice the tomatoes, onions and green peppers nicely and thin, arrange on a dish,
              placing a layer of tomatoes, an alternate layer of onion and green pepper, and
              tomatoes mixed. Dress either before bringing to the table, or at the table, with
              French dressing. This is a great <name>Creole</name> family salad, and a very healthy
              one. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <!--column 2-->
        <cb n="2"/>
        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.27_green_peppers_à_l’Espgnole">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Green Peppers à l’Espgnole.</head>
          <!--What does à l’Espgnole mean?-->
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Piments Verts en Salade à l’Espagnole.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>6<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Green Peppers</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>3<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Tomatoes</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing</ingredient>.
              </item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Parboil the peppers so that they will peel easily, and scald the tomatoes. Peel
              them, removing the seeds of the peppers. Cut the peppers into one-inch pieces, slice
              the tomatoes, and serve with plain French dressing as a salad. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.28_lentil_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Lentil Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Lentilles.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="legume">Lentils</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.7_vinaigrette_dressing">A Vinaigrette Sauce (See Recipe)</ingredient>.
              </item>
              <!--to check if this is the right ID-->
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Lentils are prepared in the same manner as Bean Salad <ptr
                target="#pic22.33_string_bean_salad">(see recipe)</ptr>, and served with Vinaigrette
              Sauce. They make a cheap, excellent and healthy salad. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.29_lettuce_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Lettuce Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Laitue.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>3 Heads of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Lettuce</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing</ingredient>.
              </item>
              <!--to check if this is the right ID-->
              <item>2<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">Eggs</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Take fresh, crisp lettuce of sufficient quantity for the number to be served, three
              young heads being enough for six. Dip in cold water examining each leaf, and pick over
              carefully, and select the fresh crisp leaves. Place all these in a salad bowl, and
              garnish nicely with sliced hard-boiled egg. Never dress the lettuce before bringing to
              the table. The vinegar causes the leaves to wilt utterly, and takes away all the
              relish which one experiences from looking at a fresh, crisp dish, and also spoils a
              fine table garnish. Bring to the table, and let the sauce, always a plain French
              dressing or Creole dressing preferred, be made at the table. Generally each makes the
              dressing to suit himself or herself, using proportions of greater or lesser quantity
              than those mentioned in the recipe. If one person dresses the salad for the table, use
              the proportions given above in any of the French salad dressings for this amount of
              lettuce. This is one of the nicest and most refreshing as well as one of the
              healthiest of all salads. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.30_louisiana_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Louisiana Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade Louisianaise.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>2<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Lettuce</ingredient>Heads.</item>
              <item>6<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">PickledCucumbers</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>2 Dozen<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Pickled Onions</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Use, in this fancy salad, lettuce, pickled cucumbers, pickled onions, cut in dice,
              and serve with a French dressing. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.31_okra_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Okra Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Fevi.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>4 Dozen Boiled Young<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Okras</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing</ingredient>.
              </item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Boil the okra as directed. <ptr target="#">(See recipe.)</ptr> When cold, dress
              nicely with <!--recipe ID for boiled okra needed-->
              <pb n="161"/>
              <cb n="1"/>
              <!--column 1--> vinegar, salt and pepper, or, if preferred, the plain French dressing,
              and serve very cold. This is a most delightful summer salad, the okra being very
              cooling in our tropical climate. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.32_spanish_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Spanish Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade à l’Espagnole.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>4 Sliced<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Tomatoes</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>2 Dozen<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Pickled Onions</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>½ Pint of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise Dressing</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> This is a very much affected salad, made of sliced tomatoes and pickled onions,
              <!--what is an affected salad? Fancy?--> prettily arranged around a small bed of
              Mayonnaise heaped in the center. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.33_string_bean_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">String Bean Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Haricots Verts en Salade.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of Cold Boiled <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">String Beans</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing (plain)</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Only very young and tender beans should be used for this salad. Boil as <ptr
                target="#">directed under the heading “Vegetables”</ptr> and put the beans in a
              salad bowl and allow to cool well. <!--to add recipe ID--> Serve with a plain French
              dressing of vinegar and a dash of Cayenne. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.34_tomato_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Tomato Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Tomates.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>4 Fresh Fine<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Tomatoes</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Slice the tomatoes nicely and place on a salad dish. Never peel or scald tomatoes
              intended for salad. Serve nicely with a plain French dressing or any of the above
              dressings. Tomatoes may also be served with Mayonnaise dressing. In this case place
              them on a bed of crisp, fresh lettuce, whole, and serve one to each person, or cut
              them in halves. Tomatoes with Mayonnaise is a luncheon dish, or a supper dish. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.35_tomato_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Iced Tomatoes.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Tomates Frappé.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>6 Whole <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Tomatoes</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Pint <ingredient corresp="#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise Sauce</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>A Garnish of Chopped Ice.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p type="instructions"> Take the tomatoes whole. Lay on a bed of lettuce or cress, as
              indicated above. Garnish with chopped ice, and serve very cold with Mayonnaise Sauce.
              This is delicious and very elegant. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.36_tomato_green_pepper_and_onion_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Tomato, Green Pepper and Onion
            Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade à la Créole.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>4<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Tomatoes</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>2<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Green Peppers</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Large Onion</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">French Dressing, Plain</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Slice the tomatoes, onions and green peppers nicely and thin; arrange on a dish,
              placing a layer of tomatoes, an alternate layer of onion and green pepper, and
              tomatoes mixed. Dress either before bringing to the table, or at the table, with
              French dressing. This is a great family salad among the <name>Creoles</name>, and a
              very <cb n="2"/> healthy one. The <name>Creoles</name> follow the old adage, that the
              taste of the onion must only lurk within the bowl when using it for salad. More than
              this renders the salad disagreeable and coarse. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.37_watercress_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Watercress Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Cresson.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Pint of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Watercress</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>Minced<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Potato</ingredient>, if desired.</item>
              <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing</ingredient>.
              </item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> This salad is made of watercress simply, or watercress and minced potatoes, mixed in
              equal quantities, and served with a French dressing. It is a most healthy, light and
              excellent salad, especially in summer. The salad is delightful without the potatoes.
              They may be added if desired. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.38_the_gardeners_wife_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">The Gardener’s Wife Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade à la Jardiniére.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Carrot</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>3<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Beets</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>½ Cup of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Green Peas</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Cup<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">String Beans</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Take fine strips of vegetables of different colors, cooked and cold, with green peas
              and string beans, and dress nicely with oil and Vinegar and serve. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.39_sardine_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Sardine Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Sardines.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>1 Box<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Sardines</ingredient>.</item>
              <item><ingredient corresp="#pic22.1_plain_french_dressings_for_salads">A Plain French Dressing</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Cut the sardines into pieces of about half an inch in length. Season nicely with a
              French dressing and serve. This is a delicious luncheon dish. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.40_potato_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Potato Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Pommes de Terre.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>3 Large Cold Boiled<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Potatoes</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>2 Hard-Boiled<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="egg">Eggs</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>9 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fat">Olive Oil</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>3 Tablespoonfuls of <ingredient type="liquid">Vinegar</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Large<ingredient type="liquid">Onion</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Teaspoonful of<ingredient type="seasoning">Salt</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>4 Sprigs of <ingredient type="seasoning">Parsley</ingredient>.</item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> This is a nice way of utilizing cold left-over potatoes. But the freshly boiled
              potatoes always make the nicest salad. Pare and peel the potatoes, if freshly boiled,
              and let them cool. Prepare the salad dressing, following implicitly the directions
              given for plain French dressing, only here the quantities are larger in proportion.
              Add the vinegar, stirring constantly. A dash of mustard may be added, if desired.
              Mince the onion very fine, and cut the potatoes into dice or slices, and mix them
              carefully with the onion. Then add the dressing, turning the potatoes into it without
              breaking. Sprinkle all with parsley, nicely chopped, and serve cold. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <pb n="162"/>
        <cb n="1"/>
        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.41_russian_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Russian Salad.</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade à la Russe.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <list>
              <item>2<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Carrots</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>2<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Parsnips</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Cup of Cold Minced <ingredient type="poultry">Fowl</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>3<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Anchovies</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Dozen<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetables">Olives</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>3<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="fruit">Caviares</ingredient>.</item>
              <item>1 Tablespoonful of<ingredient corresp="#">Sauce a la Tartare</ingredient>.</item>
              <!--find recipe ID-->
              <item>1 Teaspoonful of<ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="spice"
                  >Mustard</ingredient></item>
            </list>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> This salad is made of cooked carrots, parsnips, <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">beets</ingredient>, 
              cold roast beef, cold ham, a truffle (if it can be afforded), all cut into fancy or dice-shaped pieces. Use one
              ounce of each of the meats, or simply one cup of cold minced fowl, as it may not be
              convenient to have all these meats at hand in households. Add six boned anchovies and
              one dozen olives and two caviares, and serve with Tartare Sauce, or with a French
              salad <cb n="2"/> dressing, to which mustard has been added. It is a heavy salad. </p>
          </div>
        </div>

        <div type="recipe" xml:id="pic22.42_shrimp_salad">
          <head type="main" rend="slant(bold) align(center)">Shrimp Salad</head>
          <head type="sub" rend="align(center)">
            <foreign xml:lang="fr">Salade de Chevrette à la Mayonnaise.</foreign>
          </head>
          <div type="ingredientList">
            <item>2 Pints of Cold Boiled <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="seafood">Shrimp</ingredient>.</item>
            <item>1 Head of Crisp <ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" class="vegetable">Lettuce</ingredient>.</item>
            <item><ingredient xmlns="http://luc.edu/ctsdh/ns/1.0" corresp="#pic22.5_mayonnaise_dressing">Mayonnaise Sauce</ingredient>.
            </item>
          </div>
          <div type="instructions">
            <p> Take Lake Shrimp and River Shrimp combined, if you have them. Cut the larger Lake
              Shrimp into two. Season well with salt and pepper. Chop some lettuce. Season well.
              Place first a layer of shrimp and then of lettuce, and spread over all a Mayonnaise
              Sauce. Garnish nicely with sliced hard-boiled eggs, sliced beets and celery and
              lettuce tips, and serve very cold. </p>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
